<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news.atom"/>
  <title>Bluettipower-EU - News</title>
  <updated>2022-10-24T17:30:00+08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bluettipower-EU</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/do-solar-panels-work-on-cloudy-days</id>
    <published>2022-10-24T17:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-28T17:19:39+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/do-solar-panels-work-on-cloudy-days"/>
    <title>Do Solar Panels Work on Cloudy Days?</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Solar panels are known for generating their power from daylight - but do they work as productively in cloudy weather? Learn more here!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/do-solar-panels-work-on-cloudy-days">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>With the winter months fast approaching, the weather will soon become more unpredictable. Not only will the days become shorter and darker, but there are bound to be more clouds in the sky.</p>
<p>As solar panels draw their energy from the sun, it is a common misconception that they don’t work in cloudy or overcast conditions. However, solar panels don’t need direct sunlight to produce electricity, meaning that they will continue to work, even in adverse weather conditions.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Do Solar Panels Produce Electricity?</h2>
<p>Solar panels use <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.seai.ie/technologies/solar-energy/electricity-from-solar/" target="_blank" title="Electricity from Solar" style="color: #00aaff;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>photovoltaic (PV) cells to absorb daylight</u></a></span> and generate electrical currents to power appliances both in the home and on the go. Solar panels are made using semi-conducting substances, such as silicone, that help convert light into electricity in a more efficient way.</p>
<p>When light is absorbed by solar panels, electron particles move to create energy. This is why solar panels generally create more electricity in stronger sunlight. For instance, when the sky is clear, the most energy will be produced around midday as this is when the sun is at its highest.</p>
<p>However, this does not mean that energy cannot be absorbed by solar panels when the sun is not visible.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/use-solar-panels-to-generate-electricity-in-the-field.jpg?v=1666938302" alt="use solar panels to generate electricity in the field" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Do Solar Panels Work on Cloudy Days?</h2>
<p>As solar panels work by absorbing daylight rather than sunlight, they continue to produce electricity even on overcast days.</p>
<p>Although the productivity of solar panels is not as effective on cloudy days, they can still generate up to 25% of their usual output. Solar panels do not only absorb visible light, but also different wavelengths of light that pass through thick cloud.</p>
<p>In simple terms, as long as a shadow can be cast, solar panels can work effectively to generate electricity.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>The ‘Edge-of-Cloud’ Effect</h2>
<p>Clouds and shade can reduce the amount of energy solar panels produce, yet this is not always the case. Oftentimes, cloudy conditions can cause a higher output of electricity. This is due to a phenomenon called the ‘edge-of-cloud’ effect.</p>
<p>The effect is caused by the increase in irradiance, which results in more radiant energy being made. The reflection of the sun against passing clouds allows light to make contact with the solar panels causing higher outputs of energy to be generated.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/beautiful-cloudy-sky-in-tibet.jpg?v=1666938302" alt="beautiful cloudy sky in tibet" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2>Will Solar Panels Work in the Shade?</h2>
<p>Many factors, including natural causes, can mean that <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.thesolarcentre.co.uk/blog/2013/08/21/do-solar-panels-work-when-there-is-no-sun/" target="_blank" title="Do solar panels work when there is no sun?" style="color: #00aaff;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><u>shade will decrease the amount of energy</u></a></span> solar panels generate.</p>
<p>Although solar panel systems are engineered to prevent shading from compromising the production of energy, this is dependent on the individual solar technology – in particular, microinverters.</p>
<p>Depending on the placement of the microinverters, the panels will be affected by shading in different ways. For example, if the wires are connected to one inverter, the whole solar panel system will be affected. This will mean that the shaded panel causes the others to underperform, therefore preventing energy from passing through to the central inverter.</p>
<p>Alternatively, if the panels have their own individual microinverters, the panel which is shaded will be the only one affected, rather than the whole system.</p>
<p>This is why the overall impact of energy production will be less severe when there is multiple inverters.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>What Other Conditions Affect the Efficiency of Solar Panels?</h2>
<p>Other conditions such as the time of day and alternative weather conditions can also affect the efficiency of solar panels and their production of energy.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>During the Night</h3>
<p>Although solar panels require daylight to generate electricity, certain systems will include a backup battery storage. This backup battery allows solar panels to store excess energy from throughout the day, which can then be used during the night.  </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/super-flower-blood-moon-in-a-phase-toward-total.jpg?v=1666938302" alt="super flower blood moon in a phase toward total" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>Fog</h3>
<p>Similar to cloudy and overcast weather, foggy conditions can affect solar production. However, the panels are still able to capture some energy from the daylight.</p>
<p>Fog typically burns off throughout the day, especially during the morning. This means that by midday, the solar panels will be performing to their usual capacity, providing that the sun has returned to view.</p>
<p>It is estimated that solar panels operate at 50% of their normal efficiency when the weather is foggy, this is more than both dense cloud and overcast conditions.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Effective Are Solar Panel Systems?</h2>
<p>Whether on the go or at home, the amount of energy which is needed varies between different people and their routines. However, in order to make the most out of solar panel systems, it is important to consider their placement. It is recommended that the panels are placed on a 30-degree tilt in an open space to ensure that sufficient energy is being produced.</p>
<p>If these factors are taken into account, they can have profound effects on electricity bills. For example, utility company Eon found that a 12-panel solar system could generate enough electricity in a year to help save a household over 534€ on electricity bills!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Making the Most of Your Solar Panels</h2>
<p>Although adverse weather conditions can affect the productivity of solar panels, they don’t completely count out their efficiency. While it is clear that solar panels require daylight to generate energy, there are plenty of solutions to making the most of your systems, even on the cloudiest days!</p>
<p>When taking into consideration the different set-up requirements for solar panels in regard to local weather patterns, it is simpler than ever to naturally generate electricity.</p>
<p>Here at Bluetti, we have a range of <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/collections/solar-panels" title="BLUETTI foldable, portable, and efficient solar panels" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>foldable, portable, and efficient solar panels</u></a></span>, helping you to produce power in any location or weather condition. If you have any questions regarding solar panel systems or would like to know any additional information about our products, <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/pages/contact-us" title=" Contact BLUETTI Team to Learn More about Solar Panel Systems" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>contact our</u></a></span> expert team today!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/portable-solar-panels-introduce</id>
    <published>2022-10-17T17:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-28T17:04:32+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/portable-solar-panels-introduce"/>
    <title>Portable Solar Panels: What Are They &amp; How Do They Work?</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Looking for more information about portable solar panels, exactly? Well don't worry, we've got you covered.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/portable-solar-panels-introduce">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>With all the power you need to fuel your next adventure, portable solar panels use all the same technology as the panels on your home, albeit in a much more compact size.</p>
<p>However, unlike solar panels that you might install on your roof which are set in a fixed, rigid frame and sealed under glass, portable panels are often encased in a protective sleeve, designed to be folded and transported.</p>
<p>Discover the immense power of portable solar panels and exactly how they work here at <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/" title="BLUETTI EU: Portable Power Station, Solar Generator Kit" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>BLUETTI</u></a></span>.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/camping-with-portable-and-foldable-solar-panels.jpg?v=1666944419" alt="camping with portable and foldable solar panels" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2>What Are Portable Solar Panels?</h2>
<p>There’s no doubt that solar panels for households and businesses have become a common sight across Europe and beyond, with entire neighborhoods decorated with solar systems to help reduce energy costs. However, one solar niche was not addressed until recently, with portable solar panels now allowing solar energy to be transported anywhere at any time with ease.  </p>
<p>Whether you’re camping with friends, travelling in your campervan, or fuelling your home during a power cut, portable solar panels can provide you with the energy you need. They’re exactly what their name suggests: small sized panels designed to work on the go – priced at around half of what it would cost to have solar panels installed on your roof.</p>
<p>Unsurprisingly, portable solar panels are considered to have a limited power output when compared to fixed solar systems. However, our leading solar specialists at Bluetti have developed a range of powerful, <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/pages/portable-solar-panel" title="PORTABLE SOLAR PANEL: Harness unlimited solar power anywhere." style="color: #00aaff;"><u>portable solar panels</u></a></span> alongside portable power stations – designed to generate energy whenever and wherever you need it.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>How Do They Work?</h2>
<p>When you use portable solar panels, they keep your <a href="https://www.the-triton.com/2022/10/battle-of-the-batteries/" target="_blank" title="Battle of the Batteries: Which is right for the job?" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span><u>deep-cycle batteries</u></span></a> charged to provide power to electrical appliances. Without the need for traditional power sources such as generators, you’re free to power your appliances whenever you wish without requiring a ready supply of fuel for continued operation.</p>
<p>Portable solar panels are made up of <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.seai.ie/technologies/solar-energy/electricity-from-solar/" target="_blank" title="Electricity from Solar" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>photovoltaic cells</u></a></span> that capture and convert solar power into electricity. The portable panels are then attached to one another and connected to a battery to store the energy produced by the sun. This power can then be used to fuel electronics in the same way you would use battery power.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>The Benefits of Portable Solar Power</h2>
<p>With a large variety of portable solar panels available for all budgets and power needs, solar technology offers <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.conserve-energy-future.com/portablesolarpower.php" target="_blank" title="Solar energy is a solution for our increasing demands of energy" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>numerous benefits</u></a></span> including high efficiency and low maintenance. However, the most important benefit of portable solar panels, and the reason why most people purchase them, is the remarkable return on investment they offer.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/camping-with-bluetti-pv200-solar-panel.jpg?v=1666944419" alt="camping with bluetti pv200 solar panel" style="float: none;"></div>
<h3>High Quality Solar Cells</h3>
<p>In most cases, as with the portable solar panels available at Bluetti, portable solar panels are monocrystalline, giving them a significantly high efficiency rating.</p>
<p><span>During </span>the manufacturing process, the silicon is formed into bars and later cut into wafers of monocrystalline cells. Interestingly, the term ‘monocrystalline’ implies the use of single-crystal silicon. Due to the single-crystal silicon, electrons move more freely and as a result, provide more power from the panel to the device being charged.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Versatile</h3>
<p>Thanks to their portability, these solar panels are typically used by hikers, campers, travellers, or anyone who needs an electricity supply when not able to access grid power. However, since they come in numerous sizes, they have several other uses too.</p>
<p>While most portable solar panels are not ideal for fixed use, it’s possible for panels to form a portable power system, designed to perform on rooftops of buildings as well as on top of vehicles.</p>
<p>Alternatively, portable solar panels can be used to facilitate camping trips, charge your phone on the go, or rectify a power outage, providing a multi-use system to ease energy problems.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Weatherproof</h3>
<p>With specialist coating and protective materials, portable solar panels are designed with campers in mind with the ability to withstand any scratches and watersplash. Perfect for camping, fishing, hiking and much more, portable solar systems can be used in any weather conditions – charging even on wet and windy days.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Money Saving</h3>
<p>When thinking about saving electricity with solar panels, you might also think about which appliances and machines you can power with portable solar panels and generators. From large appliances such as refrigerators, washing machines and air conditioners to smaller electronic devices, consider utilising your solar investment with portable solutions.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Renewable Energy</h3>
<p>As climate change and global warming continue to impact our Earth, causing extreme weather, rising temperatures, melting glaciers and further devastation, the search for more sustainable solutions has never been more important.  </p>
<p>Portable solar power not only produces renewable and reliable electricity from sunlight, but also lowers the emissions of harmful greenhouse gases emitted by traditional energy backup systems. Because of this, you don’t have to worry about the environmental impact of using gasoline to power your camping gear and electrical appliances.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Our Specialist Portable Solar Panels</h2>
<p>Looking for foldable, portable solar panels? <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/collections/solar-panels" title="BLUETTI portable solar panels bring you all your power needs" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>BLUEETI portable solar panels</u></a></span> bring you all your power needs for your next adventure.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>PV200 Solar Panel 200W</h3>
<p>Connect it and leave it. <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-sp200" title="PV200: 200W BLUETTI Solar Panel " style="color: #00aaff;"><u>BLUETTI 200W</u></a></span> solar panels are set to keep your solar generators juiced as long as there’s sunlight available. Built with monocrystalline solar cells, the PV200 can convert up to 23.4% of sunlight into solar energy, charging your solar generators even in bad weather – specialist features of this panel include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>Long-lasting ETFE coating</li>
<li>
<span></span>Foldable &amp; portable</li>
<li>
<span></span>Monocrystalline solar cells with up to 23.4% efficiency</li>
<li>
<span></span>Compatible With Most Solar Generators with MC4 Connectors</li>
<li>
<span></span>12-month Warranty</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h3>PV350 Solar Panel 350W</h3>
<p>The <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/pv350" title="PV350: 350W BLUETTI Solar Panel " style="color: #00aaff;"><u>BLUETTI PV350</u></a></span> solar panel can be built into a power system to juice up your laptop, drone, refrigerator, drill and more. With a folded size of 35.6 x 24.1 x 2.5inches and 30.61lbs of weight, this panel is convenient to carry around and easy to be set up for anyone, anywhere – additional features of this panel include:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>Off-grid power supply</li>
<li>
<span></span>Foldable &amp; portable</li>
<li>
<span></span>Durable &amp; splash-proof</li>
<li>
<span></span>4% conversion rate</li>
<li>
<span></span>Wide compatibility</li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/rv-caravan-camping-at-the-caravan-holiday-park.jpg?v=1666944419" alt="rv caravan camping at the caravan holiday park" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/pages/contact-us" title=" Contact BLUETTI Team to Learn More about Portable Solar Panel " style="color: #00aaff;"><u>Contact</u></a></span> the specialist team at BLUETTI for more information and advice regarding portable solar panels.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/can-you-charge-electric-cars-with-solar-panels</id>
    <published>2022-10-10T18:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-17T18:31:18+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/can-you-charge-electric-cars-with-solar-panels"/>
    <title>Can you Charge Electric Cars with Solar Panels?</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Can you charge electric cars with solar panels?   Yes, but it's not easy or cost-effective. Read on to find out more.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/can-you-charge-electric-cars-with-solar-panels">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Electric vehicles (EVs) continue to grow in popularity, with sales of diesel and petrol vehicles on the decline.</p>
<p>EVs do not produce any toxic emissions meaning a greener and cleaner driving experience. However, driving an EV does not necessarily make for a completely climate-friendly driving experience.</p>
<p>If your electric car is charged with mains electricity, this energy will have been generated – at least in part - through the burning of fossil fuels. There is no getting away from the fact that coal and gas are essential in meeting the EU’s current power demands.</p>
<p>One way to ensure you’re using a renewable energy source is to generate your own! For many, solar energy is the most suitable and practical alternative. But what is the reality of powering your car using solar energy?</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/electric-car-using-energy-from-solar-panels.jpg?v=1665731265" alt="electric car using energy from solar panels" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2><strong>How Many Solar Panels Do I Need to Charge my EV Car?</strong></h2>
<p>The answer depends on a few different factors, including what kind of EV you have, how many miles you drive and how much sun you get too!</p>
<p>For an average-sized EV battery, 8-12 Solar panels usually generate enough energy to fully charge your car. However, if you want to know the optimum number of panels for your needs, a few calculations may help.</p>
<p>First you must calculate the daily energy (kWh) that your EV requires to fully charge. The below formula takes into consideration how many miles you drive and your car’s power consumption.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/how-to-calculate-the-daily-energy.jpg?v=1665731264" alt="how to calculate the daily energy" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>Then, use the below formula to calculate the amount of power (DC size) you require from your photovoltaic (PV) system. Factoring in peak hours of sunlight allows for an accurate estimate.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/how-to-calculate-the-amount-of-power-you-need.jpg?v=1665731264" alt="how to calculate the amount of power you need" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>Lastly, you must divide the total DC size by the generation capacity of your solar panels. The result will give you a good indication of how many solar panels you will require to charge your vehicle. However, it is not a replacement for professional advise!</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/how-to-calculate-the-amount-of-power-you-need.jpg?v=1665731264" alt="calculate the number of solar panels you need" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2><strong>How Long Does It Take to Charge an Electric Car with Solar Panels?</strong></h2>
<p>The answer to this question depends on a number of factors, such as how many miles you drive daily, where you live, your EV’s battery size and the size and efficiency of your solar system.</p>
<p>Typically, it takes between 30 minutes and 12 hours to charge the average EV.</p>
<p>Let’s use an example.</p>
<p>The Nissan Leaf is one of the best-selling pure-EVs in the EU and for this reason we’re using it in our calculations below.</p>
<p>A second-generation Nissan Leaf has a typical 4 kW solar installation and a 40kWh battery. This means it would take around 18 hours 30 minutes to fully charge the car through a regular wall plug. Understandably, this is not a convenient or indeed viable option for many!</p>
<p>However, a specially-installed EV charging point allows for quicker charging; you can expect a full charge to take around 7 hours. Whilst this option incurs an additional financial outlay, the convenience of a faster charge is worth the cost for many!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>How Do You Charge Your Electric Car Using Energy from Your Solar Panels?</strong></h2>
<p>There are a few things to consider before you start charging your EV with solar.</p>
<p>Installing a home charging unit and PV inverter is necessary for an efficient solar charging experience. The inverter converts direct currents (DC) to alternating currents (AC), generating electricity from the energy being stored.</p>
<p>Even with the growing use of electric vehicles, many people are worried about not having a charging port close to their home. A home solar charging unit is the most convenient option, allowing you to rely entirely on renewable sources too!</p>
<p>A home battery storage solution is also something to consider, especially if you want to charge your car overnight. This allows solar energy to be stored without going to waste. It is a common solution for those who use their car consistently throughout the day and cannot find time for a quick charge.</p>
<p>Check out our collection of <u><span style="color: #00a7e1;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/collections/home-battery-backup" title="BLUETTI Home Battery Backup Provides Backup Protection" style="color: #00a7e1;">home battery backups here</a></span><a href="https://www.bluettipower.com/collections/home-battery-backup">.</a></u></p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/charging-car-using-bluetti-ep500pro-power-station.jpg?v=1665731264" alt="charging car using bluetti ep500pro power station" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2><strong>Is It Worth Charging Your Car Using Solar Energy?</strong></h2>
<p>Most definitely.</p>
<p>People can be deterred by the initial upfront costs. However EU schemes are available to reduce the financial barrier to entry.</p>
<p>Ultimately, charging with solar energy allows for the cheapest, cleanest and most convenient driving experience. Using a completely renewable resource, charging your car with solar reduces your carbon footprint far beyond any other charging method.</p>
<p>Charging your car with solar energy allows for flexibility and convenience; you can even charge your car from the comfort of your own home.</p>
<p>If your solar panels generate enough energy, you might even be able to power both your house and car with them! Furthermore, solar systems often last between 25-30 years. So, once your energy saving has paid for your PV system, you could be charging your EV for free for a further 17 years or more!</p>
<p>The benefits of charging your EV with solar energy is almost endless!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>In summary, to charge your EV using solar power, you will need a large PV system - ideally 3000 watts or more. If you want to reap all the benefits of solar energy by powering your other household appliances too, you will need a larger PV system - 15,000 watts plus.</p>
<p>Our <span style="color: #00a7e1;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/pages/bluetti-solar-generator" title="BLUETTI Solar Generators are Ideal for Home or on the Road" style="color: #00a7e1;"><u>solar generators</u></a></span> provide the perfect solution. With systems suitable for all eventualities, Bluetti helps to ensure that you can power your EV and home in a convenient and efficient manner.</p>
<p>If you seek advice for what products work best for your situation, get in touch with our customer service team today!</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-to-consider-when-buying-camping-solar-panels</id>
    <published>2022-10-03T19:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-17T18:35:52+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-to-consider-when-buying-camping-solar-panels"/>
    <title>What to Consider When Buying Camping Solar Panels?</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Are you going camping soon? Read more to find solar panels for camping that are right for your needs.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-to-consider-when-buying-camping-solar-panels">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Camping provides a much-needed break from hectic day to day life, a chance to reconnect with nature and the opportunity to sleep under the stars.</p>
<p>We all have devices which are important to us, not just for comfort and connection but also for safety; we need to keep them charged.</p>
<p>The best solar panels for camping can offer an eco-friendly, clean, and efficient power supply. Whether you stay in a vehicle where panels can be fixed, or camp with a backpack and tent where portability is key, camping solar panels enable you to charge devices and appliances in an eco-friendly and efficient way.</p>
<p>Finding a solar panel that is right for your needs can be challenging. What you use it for will determine which is the best and most efficient portable solar panel for your camping needs.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/enjoying-a-cup-of-perfect-coffee-while-you-are-camping.jpg?v=1665737146" style="float: none;" alt="enjoying a cup of perfect coffee while you are camping"></div>
<h2><strong>The Top Five Things to Look for When Buying Camping Solar Panels</strong></h2>
<h3><strong> Wattage </strong></h3>
<p>Wattage is very important when considering your purchase. If you simply need to keep a phone or camera charged whilst camping, you'll only need a small charger, but if you're going to power more or bigger appliances, you'll need panels with a higher energy output.</p>
<p>The bare minimum you should look for is 2 Watts. This will allow you to charge small electronic items such as your mobile phone with around a 30-50% charge on a summer’s day.</p>
<p>If you are into photography and want to charge your DSLR or laptop, then you are going to need a little more power. 10 Watts will give you enough energy to charge both devices with around 1-3 charges a day in good sunlight.</p>
<p>If you want to charge multiple devices from your solar panel, then you will need 30+ Watts. This will allow you to charge things such as notebooks and cameras. </p>
<p>The capacity to store energy for when you know the weather isn't going to be very sunny comes in the form of a solar panel with a battery. </p>
<h3><strong>Types of Solar Panel</strong></h3>
<p>There are three main types of solar panels – monocrystalline, amorphous (thin-film) and crystalline. Monocrystalline panels are the most efficient but also the most expensive. Polycrystalline panels on the other hand, are less efficient but cost 30-50% less than its counterpart. Amorphus panels are significantly cheaper than both the other panels but are far less efficient. However, they are the most resilient and robust!</p>
<p>To ensure you are buying the most efficient solar panel, look for one made from monocrystalline solar cells. This type of high-end technology provides the highest efficiency and power capacity out of all types of solar panels.</p>
<p>BLUETTI only sells panels using this cell technology. Panels such as the <span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-sp200" title="BLUETTI 200W PV200 Solar Panel" style="color: #00aaff; text-decoration: underline;">BLUETTI PV200 Solar Panel</a></span></span> can convert up to 23.4% of sunlight into solar energy making them the choice of serious campers.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-pv200-solar-panel-is-the-choice-of-most-campers.jpg?v=1665737146" alt="bluetti pv200 solar panel is the choice of most campers" style="float: none;"></div>
<h3><strong>Size and Weight</strong></h3>
<p>The higher the wattage, the more solar cells are needed, and this in turn increases the size of the panel. The power rating dictates the size and weight of the panel overall. A panel over 200 Watts will be too heavy for everyday camping.</p>
<p>Panels of up to around 100-watts are small and light enough to carry around with you.</p>
<p>There are three main types of portable monocrystalline or polycrystalline solar panels to choose from:</p>
<ul>
<li>Rigid Solar Panel</li>
</ul>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Rigid solar panels are more suited to caravans or vehicles as they cannot be folded down to a compact size.</p>
<ul>
<li>Lightweight Folding Solar Blanket</li>
</ul>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Folding solar blankets are perfect for travelers who are worried about space and weight. Whilst they are more expensive than panels, folding solar blankets offer added convenience. For example, they can be hung off awning, draped over your car or placed over your windscreen.</p>
<ul>
<li>Freestanding Solar Panel</li>
</ul>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Freestanding solar panels can be moved and folded into a storable size. You can move them throughout the day to maximize sun exposure, making them super-efficient.</p>
<h3><strong>Consider Durability</strong></h3>
<p>Camping can be a rough activity, so you need to feel confident that your investment is going to last. Even the humble campsite poses risks to your new equipment - everything from potholes to gravel paths and the constant opening and closing of your panel will impact its lifespan.</p>
<p>Weather is a key factor and it’s essential to select a panel which is made of high-end materials. <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/pv350" title="BLUETTI 350W PV350 Solar Panel" style="color: #00aaff;">Bluetti PV350 Solar Panel</a> </span>is incredibly durable and splash-proof, boasting a handy kick stand which provides a quick and easy set up.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-PV350-solar-panel-is-essential-to-your-camping-trip.jpg?v=1665737146" alt="bluetti PV350 solar panel is essential to your camping trip" style="float: none;"></div>
<h3><strong>Cost and Warranty</strong></h3>
<p>Before you make your choice as to which type of panel to buy, it is advisable to draw up a cost to benefit analysis and consider your budget.</p>
<p>Although monocrystalline solar panels are more expensive than polycrystalline solar panels, they do offer a lot more energy for the price tag. Monocrystalline solar panels are made from superior grade silicon which has a single crystal structure, reducing resistance in the cells and allowing a better flow of electricity. This efficiency is one of the key advantages of monocrystalline solar panels.</p>
<p>It is possible to find cheap solar panels online. If you’re lucky, you might end up with one which doesn’t break the bank or break down mid-camping trip, but we would recommend buying your panels from a trusted, reputable supplier such as <u><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/" title="BLUETTI EU: Portable Power Station, Solar Generator Kit">Bluetti</a><a href="https://www.bluettipower.com/">.</a></u> </p>
<p>As with any major purchase, you want to spend more on carefully considered and sourced technology. Bluetti offer quality solar panels to suit your needs. Our solar panels offer a cost effective, durable, and reliable solution.</p>
<p>More important is the reassurance of our customer care and fantastic warranties.</p>
<p>You can rely on BLUETTI for your camping power!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-should-i-pack-for-glamping</id>
    <published>2022-09-26T19:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-10-17T18:39:25+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-should-i-pack-for-glamping"/>
    <title>What Should I Pack for Glamping?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Iggy Liu</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[What to Pack for Glamping? Here is a short guide to get you started on your glamping journey.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/what-should-i-pack-for-glamping">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Camping isn’t for everyone. The idea of ‘roughing it’ deters many from bedding down in the great outdoors. However, there is a way to enjoy sleeping beneath the stars without the creepy-crawlies, tinned beans and leaking tents!  </p>
<p>Glamping is camping in style and luxury. You’ll find that glamping facilities and accommodation are much more comfortable than a sleeping bag and tent, allowing you to stay close to nature in comfort.  </p>
<p>But if glamping is so different to camping, then what on earth should you pack? Do you still need a sleeping bag and food supplies? Well, what goes on your glamping packing list depends on the accommodation you’ve booked, the activities you’ll be doing and the facilities available. Here is a short guide to get you started on your glamping journey.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/enjoy-sleeping-beneath-the-stars-when-glamping.jpg?v=1665740677" alt="enjoy sleeping beneath the stars when glamping" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2><strong>What Can I Expect on My ‘Glamp Site’?</strong></h2>
<p>A traditional camping experience usually begins with you putting up a tent, struggling with guide ropes and then praying that it doesn’t leak or fall down. Glamping on the other hand sees you arrive at a fully functioning abode - usually a framed structure with electricity and hot running water.</p>
<p>There has been a <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20210415005724/en/World-Glamping-Market-Report-2021-Analysis-Forecasts-2020-2028---Focus-on-Cabins-Pods-Tents-Yurts-Treehouses---ResearchAndMarkets.com" style="color: #00aaff;" target="_blank" title="World Glamping Market Report 2021: Analysis &amp; Forecasts 2020-2028" rel="noopener noreferrer">surge in glamping sites</a></span> all across the world over the last decade. They come in all shapes and sizes - from a yurt to a Shepherd’s hut, a treehouse to an Iron Age round house! Not every site is all inclusive; some provide everything you need; others may just be a step up from your basic camp site. Wherever you choose to rest your head, the location and type of lodging will dictate what you need to pack.</p>
<p>Most glamping sites provide the necessities; access to running water, toilets and even toilet roll. Some sites offer showers, hot tubs and even full-sized baths! However, very few will provide towels, shower gels or shampoos, so be sure to add them to the packing list.</p>
<p>Some glamp sites provide well-stocked kitchens with basic cooking ingredients and a delicious welcome hamper, whilst others provide the basic pots, pans and crockery. However, you shouldn’t necessarily expect anything to be provided.</p>
<p>You may be given logs and kindling to use on an open fire or log burner. However, other establishments may only provide a circle of bricks for you to make your own fire. Either way, we would recommend bringing a lighter or a box of matches with you.</p>
<p>It is useful to check your host’s website prior to packing to get an understanding of the facilities and what you’ll need to bring. If you’re unsure, then pick up the phone and ask. Unlike camp sites, the range of provisions and facilities at glamp sites vary hugely. This can make it difficult to know what you need to pack; you might need to take everything, or you may just need the clothes on your back. So always double check beforehand!</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/stay-close-to-nature-in-comfort-when-glamping.jpg?v=1665740677" alt="stay close to nature in comfort when glamping" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2><strong>The Basics</strong></h2>
<p>There are some key considerations to make before you pack.</p>
<h3>Food Storage</h3>
<p>You may be provided with your own fridge or freezer. Or it may be communal which means it’s a good idea to bring a marker pen with you to write your name on all of your provisions. On the other hand, the site may not provide any food storage, so this is a key thing to consider when packing fresh food.</p>
<h3>The Bear Necessities</h3>
<p>The bathroom set up can vary widely when you’re glamping. You could have your own ensuite with a roll top bath, waterfall showers, and a log burning hot tub. Equally, there may be a hole in the ground, shared facilities or a compost toilet!</p>
<p>Knowing what the bathroom situation is will affect how you pack. You will certainly want something snuggly and warm to wear for those early hour toilet trips, especially if you have children!</p>
<p>Pack the basic toiletries; toilet roll, toothpaste, face cloth and towels. If you’re using an outdoor shower, it’s a good idea to bring organic soap, shampoo or an all-in-one hair and body wash. Your soap suds will end up in the ground so you need to use environmentally friendly products.</p>
<p>Many glamping sites take their environmental responsibilities very seriously and have a policy that bans the use of certain products. They often provide you with their own range of organic products to use. Check out if your glamping site has an online shop; you might be able to purchase their product range to take home with you.</p>
<h3>Clothing</h3>
<p>Pack as though you are going camping. Even if your site offers a more luxurious experience, you are still going to be outdoors most of the time. Most sites have a communal area for hanging out, cooking, singing songs and playing games. Pack warm clothing for the cold nights and practical, robust footwear is essential.  </p>
<h3>Your essential glamping checklist:</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>Walking boots if you plan to do any outdoor hiking or woodland exploring</li>
<li>
<span></span>Waterproof shoes for the early morning walk to the facilities</li>
<li>
<span></span>Slip on shoes are useful for getting in and out of your accommodation with ease</li>
<li>
<span></span>A lightweight, waterproof and warm coat i</li>
<li>
<span></span>Hat and gloves</li>
<li>
<span></span>A cosy blanket</li>
<li>
<span></span>Warm clothes for bedtime; even treehouses get cold at night!</li>
<li>
<span></span>Flip flops or Crocs for communal bathrooms</li>
<li>
<span></span>A hot water bottle</li>
<li>
<span></span>An extra cardigan or jumper to wear on nights when the temperature suddenly drops</li>
<li><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/collections/portable-power-station" title="BLUETTI Portable Power Station is Essential to Camping Trip"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><span style="text-decoration-thickness: initial; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;"><u>Bluetti portable power station</u></span></span></a></li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/eb70-portable-power-station-is-essential-to-your-glamping.jpg?v=1665740677" alt="eb70 portable power station is essential to your glamping" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2>Food Glorious Food</h2>
<p>Most glamping sites have basic kitchen set ups. You’re likely to find a gas stove and some pots and pans. Some sites offer catering as part of the package - barbecues and woodfired pizzas may be available, or even a restaurant or café!</p>
<p>If food isn’t offered as part of your glamping experience, bring food that is easy to prepare and cook. Pack a variety of meals that everyone can enjoy, and don’t forget to throw in a good supply of treats too!</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p>If you’re unsure what to pack, simply get in touch with your site; they are the best people to advise you! Check where the nearest supermarket is too; this gives you a backup plan if you do forget something!</p>
<p>Ultimately, as long as you have the right clothes and shoes, you can usually pick up anything you are missing whilst you’re on holiday. Hopefully our glamping packing list means you won’t be packing the kitchen sink!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-in-european-energy-crisis</id>
    <published>2022-08-19T17:17:16+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-08-22T11:00:01+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-in-european-energy-crisis"/>
    <title>The Role of Solar in the European Energy Crisis</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Discover the role of solar power in our current energy crisis right here at BLUETTI.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-in-european-energy-crisis">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div>By now, we’re all aware of the sharp increase in the cost of living. The price of food, energy, houses and more have shot up, causing a great deal of hardship for many people. And with inflation set to rise as high as 15% by 2023, our struggles are far from over.</div>
<div></div>
<p> As we look towards the future, the gas price crisis is pushing forward what the world already needed: more solar panels on rooftops. Discover the role of solar power in our current energy crisis right here at <a href="https://bit.ly/3SV2uQ1" title="Explore the BLUETTI Power Station"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">Bluetti</u></span></a>.</p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/gas-prices-surging-in-europe-as-demand-increases-globally.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="gas prices surging in europe as demand increases globally"></p>
<h2><strong>What’s Causing the European Energy Crisis?</strong></h2>
<p>Natural gas prices have been surging in Europe as demand increases globally. While this is happening with most commodities, it's been a larger problem with natural gas.</p>
<p>This is due to a global economic rebound as countries lift COVID-19 restrictions and fully reopen their economies. Markets are now competing as demand rises after the shock of the pandemic.</p>
<p>With Europe’s dependency on Russia for natural gas transportation, including crude oil and refined petroleum products, coal, steel, and iron, a current decline in supply has contributed to the energy crisis. As a result, the supply of these products has been slashed, causing their prices to soar.</p>
<p>An increased demand in Asia has also influenced energy prices, with numbers looking to inflate by <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.pwc.com/sg/en/publications/energy-transition-readiness-in-southeast-asia.html" target="_blank" title="Energy Transition Readiness in Southeast Asia" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>60% by 2040</u></a></span> – and around only 15% of this energy is renewable!</p>
<p>Globally, this ever-increasing demand will result in prices creeping up year after year, more so in times of crisis, as we have seen in the past few months.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>Looking to the Future</strong></h2>
<p>Due to the current energy crisis, and in the name of a more economically and environmentally sustainable future, governments across the world are pouring more money into sustainable alternatives. One such alternative is <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2022/feb/28/solar-panels-a-ray-of-hope-as-energy-prices-go-through-the-roof" target="_blank" title="Solar Panels is a Ray of Hope as Energy Prices Go Through the Roof" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>solar energy</u></a></span>.</p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/solar-energe-is-the-most-easily-accessible-option-available-to-home.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="solar energe is the most easily accessible option available to home"></p>
<h2><strong>The Global Impact of Solar Power</strong></h2>
<p>With energy bills on their way up again later this year, homeowners across the world are looking skywards to try and ease the pressure on their budgets through the installation of solar panels.</p>
<p><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.statkraft.com/newsroom/news-and-stories/archive/2021/statkraft-begins-work-on-irelands-largest-solar-farm/" target="_blank" title="Statkraft Begins Work on Ireland’s Largest Solar Farm" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>Ballymacarney Solar PV Park</u></a></span> will be one of Ireland’s first solar farms. With construction due to finish late this year, Ballymacarney will provide over 40,000 homes with power, helping Ireland succeed in its ambitious goal for 70% of their energy to be renewable by 2030.</p>
<p>Across the continent in Greece, this past April Hellenic Petroleum – which is currently undergoing a switch to green energy – powered up the largest bi-facial solar farm in Europe. Costing EUR 130 million to install, the <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://renewablesnow.com/news/hellenic-petroleum-brings-live-204-mw-solar-park-in-greece-780069/" target="_blank" title="Hellenic Petroleum Brings Live 204-MW Solar Park in Greece" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" style="color: #00aaff;"><u>Kozani solar park</u></a></span> will provide energy to an estimated 75,000 homes in the region.</p>
<p><strong><b> </b></strong></p>
<h2><strong>Renewable Options</strong></h2>
<p>As well as solar power, there are many other renewable sources of energy being explored by governments and homeowners across the world, such as wind, hydroelectric, and geothermal.</p>
<p>However, for a standard home located within a mild to moderate climate, solar is arguably the most effective, and most easily accessible option available to residential buyers.</p>
<p>And while solar panel installation is initially expensive, there are options available to aid buyers through their transition to renewable energy.</p>
<p>Once your solar panels are installed; your energy bills will drop. Estimates calculate savings of up to 600€ per year, potentially more as electricity prices continue to rise – and the value of your home could increase by up to 4.1%. </p>
<p><span>Interested? </span><a href="https://bit.ly/3QWgUO0" title="Contact the Bluetti Team For Advice Regarding Solar Power "><span style="color: #00aaff;">Contact</span></a><span> the </span><span>Bluetti</span><span> Team for advice regarding solar power and we’ll find the best solar solution for you. </span></p>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/most-homes-have-solar-panels-on-their-roofs-to-generate-electricity.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="most homes have solar panels on their roofs to generate electricity"></p>
<h2><strong>The Benefits of Solar Energy</strong></h2>
<p>As well as saving you money, having access to solar power can help support a more sustainable future. Renewable energy sources are currently at the forefront of global development, with more sustainable alternatives available and under construction every week.</p>
<p>Currently, the UK relies on renewable energy sources for as much as 43.1% of its energy consumption, with the goal to have zero net emissions by 2050. Across Europe and the world, similar targets are held as part of the Paris Agreement, the Kyoto Protocol, as well as individual country goals.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>How Can BLUETTI Help You?</strong></h2>
<p>Solar options at Bluetti are varied and extensive. Ranging from panels to batteries and power stations, we’ll support your move into personal renewable energy.</p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Solar Panels</h3>
<p>Solar panels are perhaps the most common method of solar power production, with approximately 1 million homes in the EU fitted with a solar installation. Both financially and environmentally smart, solar energy is an ever-increasing instrument enabling a more sustainable future.</p>
<p>BLUETTI PV series solar panels are available at 120W, 200W, and 350W. All panels are foldable and portable, allowing for use at home, out and about, in the event of an emergency, or day to day.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3K8TkLH" title="Don't miss the portable and efficient solar panels!" style="color: #00aaff;"><span style="background-color: #ffffff;">Don't miss the portable and efficient solar panels!</span></a></span></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-pv-series-solar-panels.jpg?v=1660895429" alt="bluetti pv series solar panels"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>EP500Pro Solar Generator</h3>
<p>Bluetti have also recently launched their <a href="https://bit.ly/3dE4zzx" title="BLUETTI EP500Pro Solar Power Station"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">EP500Pro Solar Generator 5100Wh</u></span></a>. This impressive generator serves as a source of back up home power boasting <span>5100Wh</span> b<span>attery capacity</span> – our generator will give you:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>40 hours running your refrigerator</li>
<li>
<span></span>300 charges of your smart phone</li>
<li>
<span></span>80 hours of LED lighting</li>
<li>
<span></span>3 hours running an electric grill</li>
</ul>
<p>Suitable for use in the home or on the go, the EP500Pro comes with a 5-year warranty.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3dE4zzx" title="Try the EP500PRO for now!" style="color: #00aaff;">Try the EP500PRO for now!</a></span></strong><a href="https://bit.ly/3dE4zzx"></a></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/buy-ep500pro-and-keep-all-your-devices-running-whenever.jpg?v=1660894920" alt="buy ep500pro and keep all your devices running whenever" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>EB70 Portable Power Station</h3>
<p>The <a href="https://bit.ly/3AwymmB" title="EB70 Could Power Multiple Devices During the Camping or RV trip."><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">EB70 portable power station</u></span></a> is a product of cutting-edge technology and design innovation. With enough force to power your essentials on the road or during energy outages, you can stay powered, wherever life takes you – our power station provides:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>50-60 charges of your smart phone</li>
<li>
<span></span>20-30 hours of LED lighting</li>
<li>
<span></span>8 hours powering your TV</li>
<li>
<span></span>3 hours running your slow cooker</li>
</ul>
<p>Whether you need a camping companion or an at-home energy solution, the EB70 comes with a 2-year warranty.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3AwymmB" title="Order the EB70 for your next adventure!" style="color: #00aaff;">Order the EB70 for your next adventure!</a></span></strong></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/EB70-protable-power-station-could-power-devices-when-camping.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="eb70 protable power station could power devices when camping" style="float: none;"></div>
<p> </p>
<h3>AC200MAX Expandable Power Station</h3>
<p>As the first modular, expandable Bluetti power station, the <a href="https://bit.ly/3AbRg13" title="BLUETTI AC200MAX Expandable Solar Generator"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">AC200MAX</u></span></a> is both powerful and reliable. Packed with an incredible 2048Wh ultra-durable LFP cells and a 2,200W full power pure sine wave inverter, the AC200MAX packs a punch off-the-grid or on the way – our all-round expandable power station will give you:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>Up to 7 hours powering your air conditioner</li>
<li>
<span></span>15-28 hours running your refrigerator</li>
<li>
<span></span>70 cups of coffee from your coffee machine</li>
<li>
<span></span>50 hours of LED lighting</li>
</ul>
<p>Struggling between power and flexibility? We’ve got you covered! With two expansion ports, the AC200MAX welcomes up to two battery ports with a 2-year warranty.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3AbRg13" title="Begin your journey with AC200MAX" style="color: #00aaff;">Begin your journey with AC200MAX</a></span></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/explore-bluetti-ac200max-solar-generator-kit.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="explore bluetti ac200max solar generator kit"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>AC300+B300 Home Battery Backup</h3>
<p>In the event of power outages or energy emergencies, power your life with <a href="https://bit.ly/3A4hNxb" title="Explore AC300+B300 Home Battery Backup"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">AC300+B300 home battery backup</u></span></a>. Suitable for various environments and designed for superior off-grid power, the AC300+B300 ensures you never run out of power – your battery backup provides:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<span></span>45 microwaved meals</li>
<li>
<span></span>3 hours powering your air conditioner</li>
<li>
<span></span>10 hours of full-size refrigerator use</li>
<li>
<span></span>180 hours of CFL lighting</li>
</ul>
<p>Expand your power at will with AC300+B300 home battery backup with a 4-year hassle free warranty.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3A4hNxb" title="Start enjoying the AC300+B300 today!" style="color: #00aaff;">Start enjoying the AC300+B300 today!</a></span></strong><a href="https://bit.ly/3A4hNxb"></a></p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/ac300_B300-power-up-to-multiple-devices-at-once-with-all-your-needs.jpg?v=1660894919" alt="ac300+B300 power up to multiple devices at once with all your needs"></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Other Solar Options</h3>
<p>Other solar options offered by Bluetti include expansion batteries, and solar generator kits. The kits are comprised of a range of solar panels, power stations, and expansion batteries, with various options available to suite all your energy requirement.</p>
<p>When considering ways to get ahead of the European energy crisis, why not begin your journey with solar energy? <a href="https://bit.ly/3QWgUO0" title="Contact BLUETTI Team for More Information about Solar Generator"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><u style="color: #00aaff;">Contact</u></span></a> the dedicated team at Bluetti for more information and advice regarding solar panels.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-panel-maintenance</id>
    <published>2022-08-15T14:15:53+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-08-15T14:18:46+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-panel-maintenance"/>
    <title>Solar Panel Maintenance: Why &amp; How to Do It?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Iggy Liu</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[How do you maintain a solar panel? Discover everything you need to know about solar panel maintenance right here at BLUETTI.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-panel-maintenance">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Homeowners who install solar power systems can receive numerous benefits: slashed electric bills, reduced carbon footprint, and potentially higher home values. With the capability to last you around 25-30 years, solar panels have plenty of time to get a return on your investment.</p>
<p>Unlike a boiler or washing machine, your solar panels are designed to work efficiently without continuous maintenance. However, to get the most value out of your solar panels and guarantee they last as long as they should, it’s important to properly maintain them. Discover everything you need to know about solar panel maintenance right here at <u><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/" title="Learn More About BLUETTI Solar Generator">Bluetti</a><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/">.</a></u></p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/solar-panel-is-important-to-maintain.jpg?v=1660379020" alt="solar panel is important to maintain" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">Solar Panel Cleaning: Is It Worth It?</h2>
<p>Dust, sap, pollution and leaves provide just a few reasons to maintain and <a href="https://solarpower.guide/solar-energy-insights/solar-panel-cleaning" target="_blank" title=" Learn Something About Solar Panel Cleaning" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><span><u>clean your solar panels</u></span></a>. Essentially, dirty panels have the same impact on solar power systems as shading does, obstructing sunlight and affecting performance.</p>
<p>Impacting both your green energy generation and <a href="https://www.seai.ie/technologies/solar-energy/electricity-from-solar/" target="_blank" title="Learn Those Technologies That Generate Electricity From Light." rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><span><u>return on investment</u></span></a>, we recommend for solar panel owners to have their system cleaned around 2-4 times per year. Alternatively, you may only need 1 cleaning per year if you live in an area with lots of rain to clear away dirt or debris.</p>
<p>If your panels are tilted, you’re fortunate enough that rainfall will naturally clear away accumulated debris. However, during summer months or extended periods without rain, it’s important to clean them manually – go ahead and try a garden hose or a leaf blower.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Do Solar Panels Require Maintenance?</h2>
<p>Solar panels ordinarily require very <a href="https://news.energysage.com/solar-panel-maintenance-overview/" target="_blank" title="Solar Panelm Maintenance Overview" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><span><u>little maintenance</u></span></a> in order to function, meaning your solar investment is often upfront and stress-free. Despite this, there are generally three solar panel maintenance schedules to consider:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Cleaning:</b></strong>Periodic light cleaning to make sure dust, debris and leaves are not obstructing the sun’s rays.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Annual inspection:</b></strong>Once per year, hire an inspector to review your solar panels and ensure they are working to their full potential.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Additional maintenance: </b></strong>If you notice a problem with your solar panels outside of your annual inspection, schedule a solar panels maintenance appointment when necessary.</li>
</ul>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/clean-the-solar-panels.jpg?v=1660379019" alt="clean the solar panels" style="float: none;"></div>
<br>
<ul></ul>
<h2>Monitoring Solar Power Performance</h2>
<p>A decrease in your panels’ energy output could indicate that your <a href="https://www.reviewgeek.com/124660/how-long-do-solar-panels-last/" target="_blank" title="How Long Do Solar Panels Last?" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><u>solar power system</u></a> requires attention. In most cases, your solar panels will not demand maintenance outside of your regular inspections and cleaning, but it’s important to consistently monitor solar panel health.</p>
<p>The most significant indicator that your solar panels need maintenance is a reduction in your energy output. Keep an eye on your electric bill as an increased bill may highlight a decline in solar energy production – in that case, it’s time to schedule a service appointment.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/monitoring-solar-power-performance.jpg?v=1660379019" alt="monitoring solar power performance" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<h2 style="text-align: left;">How Much Does It Cost per Year?</h2>
<p>We know that installing a solar panel system is a huge investment. As a result, continued <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/statistics/solar-pv-cost-data" target="_blank" title="Solar photovoltaic (PV) cost data" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer"><span><u>costs and maintenance</u></span></a> can be disheartening and frustrating. Luckily for panel owners, solar panel maintenance costs will be minimal, meaning you can enjoy sustainable solutions without an ongoing additional expense.</p>
<p>It’s important to understand that if you give your system a bit of love and care, you will be rewarded with roughly 30 years of solar energy in return. Additionally, a lot of manufacturers will provide a guarantee for any issues that arise within the first 10-25 years. Some providers even include several maintenance visits in your solar panel purchase!</p>
<p>An annual solar panel service can cost between £100 and £200 a year depending on the provider.</p>
<p>A further solar panel maintenance cost you need to know about relates to the inverter; the key part of the unit which converts the DC output of your panels into the AC required by your local power grid.</p>
<p>The inverter has an average lifespan of around 25 years, after which it will need replacing as a cost between £800 and £1,000. While this may seem like a large sum, remember you’re awarding yourself 25 additional years of solar power.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Solar Panel Maintenance Checklist</h2>
<p>We have established that a little solar panel maintenance goes a long way, but how can homeowners keep track of this process. Consider a solar panel maintenance checklist to ensure it is always performing at its best:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Personally examine your solar panels</b></strong>: Check your solar panels 2-4 times per year to ensure they are clean and secure.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Check in on your online monitoring system:</b></strong>Many systems come with a tool / app to track daily output.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Monitor electricity bills:</b></strong>If your electricity bill has gone up, it’s a good sign that you should schedule a service appointment.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Keep a logbook of maintenance:</b></strong>Once per year, hire an inspector to review your solar panels. It is useful to keep a record of maintenance if there are any issues that may need diagnosing in the future.</li>
<li>
<b><span></span></b><strong><b>Replace the inverter:</b></strong>You can expect your inverter to last around 25 years, depending on the model and environmental conditions. Regular inspections can help to determine whether your inverter needs replacing.</li>
</ol>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/solar-panel-is-work-efficiently-when-traveling.jpg?v=1660379019" alt="solar generators are a necessity for travel" style="float: none;"></div>
<br>
<ol></ol>
<h2>Maintaining Your Solar Panels</h2>
<p>Protecting and caring for your investment is essential to owning any item, and solar panels are no exception. Thankfully, solar panels are incredibly durable and designed to require little to no maintenance. Despite this, regular cleaning and annual inspections will ensure that your panels are performing to the best of their ability year on year.</p>
<p>If you notice dust, debris or snow piled up on your system, a routine clean will ensure that your panels continue to operate efficiently. Additionally, consider investing in panels with a good warranty so if your panels do break, they’ll get replaced. </p>
<p>With these tips, you can keep your solar panels functioning well and producing the power they are designed for. If you have any questions about solar power maintenance and taking care of your system, <a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/" title="BLUETTI Bring You All Your Power Needs "><span><u>contact Bluetti</u></span></a> today.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/best-solar-panels-for-campervan</id>
    <published>2022-07-28T14:51:19+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-28T15:20:04+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/best-solar-panels-for-campervan"/>
    <title>What Are the Best Solar Panels for Campervan?</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>With so many campervan solar panels on the market, how do you choose? Read our guide on choosing the best campervan solar panels!</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/best-solar-panels-for-campervan">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/use-solar-panels-to-generate-electricity-while-traveling.jpg?v=1658980456" alt="use solar panels to generate electricity while traveling"></p>
<p>You are planning your next adventure with your campervan and do not want to rely on the power solution on the campsite, or you are planning a bigger for an extended period of time? Then the solution with solar energy is both cost-efficient and eco-friendly.</p>
<h2><strong>Is It Worth to Buy a Campervan Solar Panel?</strong></h2>
<p>When you are out in nature, or on a trip on the weekend and you need your electronic devices to work properly, or you want a cold drink and nice food that stays fresh? Then you really want to consider a good solution for your electrical supply during your off grid adventures. There are different solutions, but the power of a solar panel for your campervan is clean and easy. Also if you want to work, while you are on the go, with a solar panel for your campervan, you can.</p>
<h2><strong>What Type of Solar Panel is Best for a Camper?</strong></h2>
<p>There are different types of solar panels. There are glass panels, flexible panels and foldable panels, which you can easily carry. The glass panels and the flexible panels take up a lot of space and are best, if you would like to mount something you your campervan.</p>
<p>The most flexible and easiest solution are the foldable solar panels. When you arrive at your desired spot, hook them up in 5 seconds with your bluetti solar generator, for example the <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-poweroak-eb70" title="Learn about bluetti protable EB70 power station" style="color: #00aaff;">eb70</a></span>, and keep collecting sunlight independently. When the earth moves and the sun is at an inefficient angle, adjust the solar panel for your campervan within seconds.</p>
<p>If you travel with your campervan and want to work outside, in the beautiful nature just hundred meters away from your campervan, the portable solar panel comes in very handy. You can literally work from anywhere.</p>
<h2><strong>How Many Solar Panels Do I Need for My Campervan?</strong></h2>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/solar-panel-will-keep-the-generators-running.jpg?v=1658980457" alt="solar panel will keep the generators running" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>The amount of solar panels you need for your campervan depends on the solar generator you use. If you use the smaller and lighter <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-ac50s" title="Learn about ac50s solar generator " style="color: #00aaff;">Bluetti ac50s</a></span>, you can recharge your device with the SP120 solar panel within 4-5 hours.</p>
<p>If you have the bigger <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-eb55-power-station" title="EB55 power station is an ideal solution for campervan" style="color: #00aaff;">Bluetti eb55</a></span> with an extraordinarily high lifecycle of 2500+ then you can decide if you want to use the SP120 or the PV200. With the 120W Panel it takes just over 6 hours and with the bigger 200 W panel it takes you 4-5 hours from 0-100.</p>
<p>If your power demand is a bit higher you would enjoy using the <span style="color: #00aaff;"><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-poweroak-eb70" title="EB70 is an excellent backup power source " style="color: #00aaff;">Bluetti EB70</a></span> with a higher power delivery, and you can also charge it with both, the SP120 and the PV200. With the SP120 it takes 7-8 hours and with the PV200 it takes 5-6 hours to fully charge.</p>
<p>So the decision on which is the best panel for campervans, comes down to the solar generator you are using. Every solar generator has a maximum Input and if your solar panel is too big, it will not work as expected.</p>
<h2><strong>What Are Recommend BLUETTI Solar Panels for Campervans?</strong></h2>
<p>At the moment there are three different Solar panels available. All of them are top quality, durable and are water resistant. So if it suddenly starts to rain, it is not much of a problem. The panels are foldable and have the ability to stand alone. </p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{5fdaa6ae-521f-8288-60b1-8c26a6ab92a7-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h3 class="p">SP120 – 120W Solar Panel</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-sp120" title="BLUETTI SP120 Solar Panel"><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-sp120-solar-panel_480x480.jpg?v=1658992138" alt="bluetti sp120 solar panel" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></strong></a></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{9ed5eb6f-e6e9-e4fe-eb15-261895f474e5-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<p class="p"><span>All panels come with the same rugged and durable features that have a water and dust resistant IP54 rating. With just above 4 kg the SP120 is extremely lightweight.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>cell efficiency of up to 23%</li>
<li>lightweight 4,3 kg</li>
<li>small packing size of 41,5 x 41 cm  </li>
<li>operating range of -10°C -+65°C</li>
</ul>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{f154dd45-bc08-9147-c429-99583d29cf43-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h3 class="p">PV200 – 200W Solar Panel</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-sp200" title="BLUETTI PV200 Solar Panel"><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-pv200-solar-panel_480x480.jpg?v=1658992304" alt="bluetti pv200 solar panel" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></strong></a></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{e426d361-a9da-36ab-9b0e-5d52bd1dc20b-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<p class="p"><span>The slightly bigger brother of the SP120 comes in with 6,5 kg and has the same durability of IP54, with an even higher cell efficiency. If the small change in Size and weight does not make a difference for you, then you should consider the P</span><span>V</span><span>200.</span></p>
<ul>
<li>
<span>cell efficiency of up to 2</span><span>3.4</span><span>%</span>
</li>
<li>
<span>lightweight </span><span>7</span><span>,</span><span>3</span><span> kg</span>
</li>
<li>
<span>small packing size of 5</span><span>9</span><span> x </span><span>60</span><span> cm  </span>
</li>
<li><span>operating range of -10°C -+65°C</span></li>
<li><span>Best Working Temperature: 77℉ (25℃)</span></li>
</ul>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{1168f238-20a3-c5ed-67c4-b557eda84518-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h3 class="p">PV350 – 350W Solar Panel</h3>
<p><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/pv350" title="BLUETTI PV350 Solar Panel"><strong><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-pv350-solar-panel_480x480.jpg?v=1658992341" alt="bluetti pv350 solar panel" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></strong></a></p>
<p><span>If you have a big solar generator and do not mind to carry a bit more with you, the PV350 will fit your needs perfectly. But keep in mind to use the right solar generator with it. You should at least use the Bluetti ac200p with it, but then you can take two of them at the same time. </span></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{e992ef8f-5af5-0cde-24a2-87fe1afa9de9-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<ul>
<li><span>Cell efficiency of up to 23,4%</span></li>
<li><span>13,9 kg</span></li>
<li><span>small packing size of 90,5 x 61,3 cm  </span></li>
<li><span>operating range of -10°C -+65°C</span></li>
</ul>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{bdeeba9b-4a3c-cf70-a42d-fe0be51aa2fb-64228783742}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h2 class="p"><strong>FAQ</strong></h2>
<p class="p"><span style="color: #00aaff;">1.Is it difficult to set up an off grid power system?</span></p>
<p class="p">No, the combination of solar generator and the specially designed potable panels are plug and play.</p>
<p class="p"><span style="color: #00aaff;">2.How durable are the Solar Panels?</span></p>
<p class="p">The Bluetti Solar Panels are very durable and of the highest quality. They are dust proof and water resistant with an IP54 certification.</p>
<h2><strong>Final Thoughts</strong></h2>
<p>If you are searching for the best solar panel for campervan, it is necessary that you think of the power demand you have. If you use your mini fridge, charge your camera, drone, laptop and other devices you may consider taking the <span style="color: #000000;">Bluetti PV200,</span> because it has the best size to wattage ratio and the highest cell efficiency. It is just slightly bigger than<span style="color: #000000;"> the Bluetti SP120 but</span> still portable enough for taking it somewhere even more remote. Sure you will enjoy your flexible and high quality solar panel for your campervan.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<script type="application/ld+json">// <![CDATA[
{
  "@context": "https://schema.org/",
  "@type": "FAQPage",
  "mainEntity": [
    {
      "@type": "Question",
      "name": "Is it difficult to set up an off grid power system?",
      "acceptedAnswer": {
        "@type": "Answer",
        "text": "No, the combination of solar generator and the specially designed potable panels are plug and play."
      }
    },
    {
      "@type": "Question",
      "name": "How durable are the Solar Panels?",
      "acceptedAnswer": {
        "@type": "Answer",
        "text": "The Bluetti Solar Panels are very durable and of the highest quality. They are dust proof and water resistant with an IP54 certification."
      }
    }
  ]
}
// ]]]]><![CDATA[></script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-camping</id>
    <published>2022-07-21T18:23:08+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-21T18:23:08+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-camping"/>
    <title>What to Consider Before Buying a Camping Solar Generator？</title>
    <author>
      <name>XIANGZHU YIN</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Planning a camping trip? To improve your camping experience, try to use a solar generator!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-camping">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{33dba62f-946f-2dcb-e039-a674d97248b3-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'" style="text-align: start;">
<p class="p"> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/solar-generator-is-essential-for-camping_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658398472" alt="solar generator is essential for camping"></p>
<h2 class="p"><span>What is A Solar Generator?</span></h2>
<p class="p"><span>You basically have to think of a solar generator like a giant battery that powers all the technical equipment you would want to use on your camping trip. But that’s not all, with a solar generator you can combine the big battery with a long lifecycle with a solar panel which extends your trip as long as you have the time for it. Power, while outside or on the road is no longer an issue.</span></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{c55088a1-3a9c-2ae3-f8c1-08f528309eee-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h2 class="p"><span>Why to Bring A Solar Generator in Camping?</span></h2>
<p class="p"><span>Solar Power is becoming the most popular and hassle-free solution for self-sustained travel. No matter if you are on a short trip over the weekend or on an extended tour through the continent. Most campsites charge you high prices for using their power connection. So, for camping a solar generator is the perfect solution with no emissions and no running costs. The green energy while you are on the go.</span></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{ea45e6a0-9edf-3b8a-3eaa-d9fe652dc35a-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h2 class="p"><span>What to Consider Before Buying a Camping Solar Generator<span face="宋体" style="font-family: 宋体;">？</span></span></h2>
<p class="p"><span>When you plan to buy a solar generator for camping, you may think of the products you want to power with. There are some important things to consider. Some homeware requires a large amount of wattage, while running. So to power these different types of you have to look at the technical details. Most importantly you would want to look at the maximum sustained wattage for your solar generator while camping, because this tells you what you could operate. The second thing you want to think of is the battery capacity. This is especially important for days, where you are unable to recharge the battery.</span></p>
</div>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{b2b159ba-44c6-4ccc-56fe-ffd422ded471-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h2 class="p"><span>What Are BLUETTI's Best Solar Generators for Camping?</span></h2>
<p class="p"><span>Besides the technical capabilities of the solar generator, for camping you would also want to think of size and weight. Additionally, the bluetti batteries use very safe Batteries with a high lifecycle that exceeds many other manufacturers. There are mainly three different solar generators you would want to consider for long lasting trips with enough power to keep you working.</span></p>
<p class="p"> </p>
</div>
</div>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{b85b674e-b5c9-6ff5-aeec-1307e0d7bdd2-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'" style="text-align: start;">
<h3 class="p"><span>AC50S Solar Generator</span></h3>
<p class="p"><span>The first and most portable solar generator is the </span><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-ac50s" title=" perfect to use at home, in a campervan, or on a camping trip"><span><u><span class="15">bluetti ac50s</span></u></span></a><span> which has a 500Wh capacity and a maximum wattage of 300W which lets you use various devices from a phone all up to a projector for your own outdoor cinema.</span></p>
<p class="p"><span>The super safe battery lets you run your devices. If you want to know how long your devices will run, you can calculate it by using 500Wh*0,85/Power of the device = Hours of use</span><span></span></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{0779479b-bc66-933c-9eeb-9bac2078ef51-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'" style="text-align: start;">
<p class="p"><span>The solar generator charges with solar panels up to 120W, with wall outlet and also with the 12V from your car!</span></p>
<p>Detail overview:</p>
<ul>
<li>500 Wh battery capacity</li>
<li>300 W output power</li>
<li>11 Power outputs</li>
<li>4-5 hours for full recharging with the 120 W, SP120 panel</li>
<li>45 W quick charging USB-C outlet</li>
<li>1000+ lifecycles</li>
<li>pure sine wave</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="p"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/bluetti-solar-generator-in-the-wild_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658398558" alt="bluetti solar generator in the wild"></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{d5c3f04f-b176-ea19-1f27-2e97d4c47e17-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h3 class="p"><span></span></h3>
<h3 class="p"><span></span></h3>
<h3 class="p"><span>EB55 Solar Generator</span></h3>
<p class="p"><span>If you want to combine a higher load of output, a good amount of capacity in a portable format, the </span><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-eb55-power-station" title="EB55 could run most of your essential outdoor appliances"><span><u><span class="16">bluetti eb55</span></u></span></a><span> may be the right choice for you. You can bring it along and power all your devices, as long as they don’t exceed 700W. The eb55 is with its 6,5 kg small enough to carry it comfortably for longer distances and powerful enough to run different devices at the same time. If you want to charge you phone contactless, this is possible as well.</span></p>
<p class="p"><span>The solar generator charges with solar panels up to 200W, with wall outlet, also with the 12V or 24V from your car and even from a generator!</span></p>
<p class="p">Detail overview:</p>
<ul>
<li><span>537 Wh battery capacity</span></li>
<li>
<span>700 W output power</span> </li>
<li><span>11 Power outputs</span></li>
<li><span>4-5 hours for full recharging with the 200 W, PV200 solar panel</span></li>
<li><span>100 W quick charging USB-C outlet</span></li>
<li><span>2500+ lifecycles with durable LiFePO4 battery</span></li>
<li><span>pure sine wave</span></li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="p"><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/power_your_home_with_EB55_solar_generator.jpg?v=1658388771" alt="power your home whenever power outages occur" style="float: none;"></p>
<h3 class="p"> EB70 Solar Generator</h3>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{8b3fde7f-4300-ddb1-7059-2516bede2c08-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'" style="text-align: start;">
<p class="p"><span>The massive 716 Wh capacity combined with the 1000W makes the </span><a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-poweroak-eb70" title="EB70 power station is the right choice for you when camping"><span><u><span class="15">bluetti eb70</span></u></span></a><span> the ideal solar generator for your camping trip. It is just under 10 kg and fits in almost every camping setup. With the high 1000W output you can power your portafilter machine and deliver perfect coffee while you are on the go and don’t forget to bring your waffle iron to accompany the delicious coffee. The eb70 will make a whole new experience out of your camping trip. Charge your laptop, drone, camera and phone at the same time, while watching a movie.</span></p>
<p class="p"><span>The solar generator charges with solar panels up to 200W, with wall outlet, also with the 12V or 24V from your car and even from a generator!</span></p>
<p class="p"><span>Detail overview:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span>716 Wh battery capacity</span></li>
<li><span>1000 W output power</span></li>
<li><span>9 Power outputs and 1 wireless charging pad</span></li>
<li>5-6 hours for full recharging with the 200 W, PV200 solar panel</li>
<li>100 W quick charging USB-C outlet</li>
<li>2500+ lifecycles with durable LiFePO4 battery</li>
<li>pure sine wave</li>
</ul>
<p class="p"> </p>
</div>
<p> <img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/get-power-with-bluetti-ac50s-solar-generator_1024x1024.jpg?v=1658398721" alt="get power with bluetti ac50s solar generator"></p>
<div ksdocclipboard="ksDocClipboardId:'{b641a4ac-4f5e-3e09-0729-a26fb2d4b4bb-64228900550}';from:'wps';priorityFormat:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format';mimetypes:'Kingsoft WPS 9.0 Format;text/html'">
<h3>FAQ</h3>
<p><span style="color: #00aaff;">1. How long will my solar generator power my devices?</span></p>
<p>You can calculate it easily by using this: Estimated hours of use = 716Wh (for the EB70) *0,85/Power of the device</p>
<p><span style="color: #00aaff;">2. Can I charge and discharge at the same time?</span></p>
<p>Yes. But it is recommended not to do so, for an extended battery life.</p>
<p><span style="color: #00aaff;">3. Can I do anything to extend my battery life?</span></p>
<p class="p">Yes. You can make sure not to charge and discharge fully. If you keep your solar generator at a level between 20-80% you extend the lifecycles massively.</p>
<p class="p"> </p>
<h3 class="p"><span>Final Thoughts</span></h3>
<p class="p"><span>If you are searching for the best solar generator for camping, there are a few things you would want to keep in mind. First you should look at the devices you are planning to power and secondly you would have to think about the duration you want to last, without recharging the device with solar. If you are planning to get the EB55 or the EB70, you can also change between two solar panels, the SP120 and the PV200 which changes the time of recharging. If you have figured out these questions you are good to go, and your adventures can start without compromises.</span><span></span></p>
<p> </p>
</div>
</div>
</div><script type="application/ld+json">
{
  "@context": "https://schema.org/",
  "@type": "FAQPage",
  "mainEntity": [
    {
      "@type": "Question",
      "name": "How long will my solar generator power my devices?",
      "acceptedAnswer": {
        "@type": "Answer",
        "text": "How long will my solar generator power my devices?"
      }
    },
    {
      "@type": "Question",
      "name": "Can I charge and discharge at the same time?",
      "acceptedAnswer": {
        "@type": "Answer",
        "text": "Yes. But it is recommended not to do so, for an extended battery life."
      }
    },
    {
      "@type": "Question",
      "name": "Can I do anything to extend my battery life?",
      "acceptedAnswer": {
        "@type": "Answer",
        "text": "Yes. You can make sure not to charge and discharge fully. If you keep your solar generator at a level between 20-80% you extend the lifecycles massively."
      }
    }
  ]
}
</script>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-vs-generator-technology-contrasted</id>
    <published>2021-08-03T10:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:25:56+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-vs-generator-technology-contrasted"/>
    <title>Solar Generator vs Generator (Technology contrasted)</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Solar generator vs. generator, what are the benefits and drawbacks of both technologies, how do they compare against one another, which innovation is better?<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/solar-generator-vs-generator-technology-contrasted">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[Solar generator vs. generator, what are the benefits and drawbacks of both technologies, how do they compare against one another, which innovation is better?<br><br>If these are several of the questions you find yourself asking, after that, you have discovered the best article!<br><br>As we have actually already gone over in <a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021" title="LEARN ABOUT THE BACKGROUND OF SOLAR POWER (1839 - 2021).">this post</a>, the solar result was uncovered in 1839 by Alexandre-Edmond Becquerel.<br><br>Since then, modern solar technology has been creating at a rapid rate.<br><br>In fact, solar prices have dropped more than 70% in the past couple of years.<br><br>These significant cost drops have actually made innovations like solar generators far more accessible to the public.<br>
<h1>SOLAR GENERATOR VS GENERATOR.</h1>
<meta charset="utf-8"><br><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0536/3390/8911/files/Solar_generator_vs_generator_1024x1024.jpg?v=1626204169" alt="solar generator vs generator">
<div class="TableWrapper">
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong></strong></td>
<td><strong>Solar Generator</strong></td>
<td><strong>Gas Generator</strong></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Average Price</strong></td>
<td>$1700</td>
<td>$1000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Noise Level (7m)</strong></td>
<td>7dB</td>
<td>70dB</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Ease of Use</strong></td>
<td>Press a button to start</td>
<td>Complicated start up </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Environment</strong></td>
<td>Zero CO2</td>
<td><span>500g/H CO2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Average Weight</strong></td>
<td> 59 Pounds</td>
<td>+55 Pounds</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Running Cost</strong></td>
<td>Zero</td>
<td>Ongoing costs</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
 <br>( In the graph above, we compared the basic <a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-ac200p-power-station" title="BLUETTI AC200P 2000WH/2000W SOLAR PORTABLE POWER STATION (EU-VERSION)">Bluetti AC200P</a> 2000 watt solar generator with a conventional 2000 watt gas generator.).<br><br>We will compare the solar generator vs. generator in full a little later in our short article. For now, we wish to describe both innovations.<br>
<h1>WHAT IS A SOLAR GENERATOR?</h1>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/0714-2.jpg?v=1628849206" alt="bluetti ac200p power station charging with solar panel"></p>
A solar generator is capable of capturing the sun's power through attachable photovoltaic panels. These solar panels have the ability to transport claimed energy to an interior storage space system (which is generally comprised of lithium-ion technology, it deserves noting that our most recent solar generators utilize <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lithium_iron_phosphate_battery" title="LiFePO 4 battery">LiFePO4 battery</a> technology).<br><br>Solar generators are normally comprised of the following technology:<br>
<ul>
<li>Solar Panels.</li>
<li>Inverter.</li>
<li>Cost controller.</li>
<li>Battery.</li>
</ul>
<h1>HOW DOES A SOLAR GENERATOR WORK?</h1>
Solar generators function by incorporating a solar panel, fee controller, a battery system, and an inverter right into a portable system that can transform as well as save solar power, which can, after that, be changed right into a useable electric existing.<br>
<h2>SOLAR PANELS:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Solar generators can be acquired with or without solar panels. If you do not have solar panels, you will require to recharge your gadget through another source of power. Although, one of the most reliable means to run a solar generator is by means of solar panels. Your solar panels will convert the sunlight's power into electricity.</li>
</ul>
<h2>INVERTER:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Our solar generators all come with the most up-to-date built-in pure sine wave innovation. Inverters are used to transform your solar generators kept electrical energy from straight existing (DC) to rotating existing (Air Conditioner). The factor for this conversion is straightforward. A lot of the appliances we all own operate, making use of the alternating present.</li>
</ul>
<h2>FEE CONTROLLER:</h2>
<ul>
<li>BLUETTI solar generators all feature the current constructed in MPPT solar cost controller modern technology. The key objective of charge controllers is to prevent your solar panels from overcharging (therefore harmful) your built-in battery.</li>
</ul>
<h2>BATTERY:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Possibly one of the most crucial facets of a solar generator is the battery. BLUETTI's most recent models come with the most effective battery modern technology: LiFePO4. All that power is generated from your solar panels requires to be stored somewhere. That is where your battery is available; it is able to keep large quantities of solar energy at any kind of one provided time. A lot of solar generators are rated by their capacity as well as are an indicator of just how many/how long they will certainly be able to charge or power tools.</li>
</ul>
<h1>WHAT IS A GAS GENERATOR?</h1>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/Gasoline-Generator-768x596.jpg?v=1628849401" alt="GAS GENERATOR" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>A generator transforms kinetic energy (motion) into electrical energy.<br><br>A generator typically contains the following components:</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<ul>
<li>Engine</li>
<li>Alternator</li>
<li>Fuel System</li>
<li>Voltage Regulator</li>
<li>Cooling and Exhaust Systems</li>
<li>Lubrication System</li>
<li>Battery Charger</li>
<li>Control Panel</li>
</ul>
<p>As you can currently see, when it involves solar generators vs. generators, generators are comprised of a lot more parts. A lot of these components are relocating, and this is the reason gas generators require even more ongoing upkeep.</p>
<h1>
<br>HOW DOES A GAS GENERATOR WORK?</h1>
<p>It transforms kinetic energy (activity) into power. It does this by utilizing a spinning electromagnet (armature) to create an electrical current via a fixed magnetic field (stator). This kinetic energy is normally implemented by shedding either gas or oil.</p>
<h2>
<br>ENGINE:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The engine is where it all begins for the gas generator. It's the source of the input mechanical energy to the generator. The maximum power output of the generator is directly pertaining to the size of the engine. Remember that the maker of the engine should be gotten in touch with to obtain maintenance schedules.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>ALTERNATOR:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The generator is additionally known as the "genhead" and also is in charge of creating the electric outcome from the mechanical input supplied by the engine. It is made up of fixed and relocating components, which are all framed in housing. All these elements interact to trigger a loved one activity between the magnetic and also electric fields. This is what actually creates electrical energy.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>GAS SYSTEM:</h2>
<ul>
<li>The majority of gas storage tanks linked to generators need to have enough capacity to keep the generator functional for 6 to 8 hours typically. Small generators normally have their tanks as part of the skid base or are improved top of the generator's framework.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>VOLTAGE REGULATORY AUTHORITY:</h2>
<ul>
<li>This component manages the outcome voltage of the gas generator. It virtually does the same thing as the solar generator's inverter. It transforms Air Conditioning to DC and also feeds this to the relevant elements, which cycle it between A/C to DC and DC to AC. This cycle proceeds till the generator is able to generate outcome voltage equal to its full operating capacity.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>AIR CONDITIONING &amp; EXHAUST SYSTEM：</h2>
<ul>
<li>Freshwater is normally used as a coolant for small generators or very large devices over 2250 kW as well as over. Hydrogen can likewise be used as a coolant for the stator windings of big generator devices. Hydrogen is normally extra efficient at absorbing warmth than other coolants. When it comes to the exhaust, it is unbelievably important that an appropriate system is made use of. Fumes released by a generator are similar to fumes from any other diesel or fuel engine as well as consist of highly poisonous chemicals. Carbon monoxide gas poisoning continues to be among the leading causes of death among blog post-hurricane-impacted areas.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>LUBRICATION SYSTEM:</h2>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Unlike solar generators, gas generators consist of many moving components in the engine compartment. Consequently, it needs ample lubrication to guarantee that every little thing continues to be smooth and also durable for an extended period of time. The generator's engine is normally lubed by oil stored in a pump. It is important that once in a while, you inspect the degree of lubrication oil (every 8 hours). You also need to take note of any type of indicator of oil leaks and must transform the engine oil every 500 hrs of generator procedure.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>BATTERY CHARGER:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Most gas generators' start function is battery operated. The onboard battery charger maintains the generator battery charged by supplying it with an accurate float voltage. If the float voltage is too low, the battery will remain under billed. If it is too high, it will damage the battery. Many battery chargers are completely automatic and do not require any type of changes to be made or any type of settings to be altered.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>CONTROL PANEL:</h2>
<ul>
<li>This is the user face that is included on a lot of contemporary generators. They likewise include provisions for electric outlets as well as controls. Various suppliers have actually carried user face functions which could consist of electric start as well as shut-down, the engine determines, generator evaluates.</li>
</ul>
<h1>
<br>WHICH KINDS OF GENERATORS DO YOU NEED?</h1>
<p><br>We will break this section up into two situations. Each scenario will certainly offer you a basic idea of when each kind of generator will certainly be the most beneficial to you.<br><br></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h1>SCENARIO 1.</h1>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/IG-0805-2.jpg?v=1628851090" alt=""></p>
<p><br>Wintertime is turning up, and also you live in a location with high amounts of blizzards and also snowfall. You want to make certain that if the power goes out throughout this time around that, you will certainly have sufficient power to run all your most important home appliances such as your heating system and also some lights.<br><br>In this circumstance, having a backup source of power that does not depend on sunlight is optimal. As long as you have sufficient fuel, you will certainly be able to generate your very own electricity for as long as you require.<br><br>All it takes is some insight into establishing the gas generator up close to your home to run an extension cable. Nevertheless do keep in mind you don't desire it as well near to your residence or the fumes will certainly enter your house.</p>
<h1>
<br>SCENARIO 2.</h1>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/6_800x_1c0e20af-aa8c-4641-9155-2ff0c2f117fa.jpg?v=1628851142" alt=""><br>If you require backup power to your residence during summer, after that, there is no doubt our <a href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/products/bluetti-eb55-537wh-700w-solar-power-station" target="_blank" title="bluetti-eb55-537wh-700w-solar-power-station" rel="noopener noreferrer">most recent solar generator</a> is your best choice. It can store more than enough power to power all your home appliances for a couple of days and even weeks.<br><br>Additionally, smaller-sized solar generators additionally beam when it pertains to outdoor camping as well as the outdoors.<br><br>Solar energy generators are environment-friendly as well as make absolutely no noise, practically essential if you are out outdoor camping in the timbers.<br><br>Unlike gas generators, as soon as your solar generator is established (that is, the solar panels have been placed properly towards the sunlight), you can ignore it. There is no refueling needed. The longer it's out in the sunlight, the more it's gathering.</p>
<h1>
<br>5 ADVANTAGES OF UTILIZING A SOLAR GENERATOR.</h1>
<h2>1. TOTALLY FREE CLEAN POWER FROM THE SUN.</h2>
<p>When you use a solar generator, you are basically utilizing free power from the sunlight instead of making use of pricey filthy nonrenewable fuel sources. You can proceed with getting this free energy from the sun for the life expectancy of your solar panels, which is normally around 25 to three decades.</p>
<h2>2. LOW MAINTENANCE EXPENSES.</h2>
<p>Unlike the majority of traditional fuel or gas generators, solar generators have definitely no relocating components as well as do not make use of a fluid fuel. No moving parts indicate that the chance you will require to pay for any type of sorts of repair service is dramatically lower.</p>
<h2>3. SILENT As Well As TIDY OPERATION.</h2>
<p>Other than the noticeable economic gains of using a solar generator, selecting this environment-friendly modern technology over various other nonrenewable fuel source systems has different ecological upsides. Gas-powered generators bring about air pollution alongside sound pollution, and while the latter is just simply bothersome, the former contributes to climate change.</p>
<h2>
<br>4. IT'S AN FINANCIAL INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITY.</h2>
<p>The general lifespan of a solar panel is 25 to thirty years. While gas-powered generators do have lengthy lifespans, normally 20 to 40 years, they do not come without trouble. You will certainly need to execute numerous upkeep tasks on them to maintain them functional. Furthermore, you will certainly require to continuously buy them sustain in order to make use of the tool. Solar-powered generators require no such tasks.</p>
<h2>
<br>5. LIGHT AND ALSO EASY.</h2>
<p>Many sturdy gas-powered generators can weigh significant amounts, often up to 250 pounds. Our heavy-duty solar-powered EP500 Pro evaluates a plain 182 extra pounds in contrast. Clearly, the much less effective the generator, the lighter it typically evaluates but in recap, solar generators evaluate a lot less than gas-powered generators.</p>
<h1>FINAL THOUGHTS.</h1>
<p>If you are contrasting solar generators vs. generators, then we hope after reading this article, you have a better understanding of all the differences entailed between both modern technologies.<br><br>If you have any more inquiries focusing on solar generators, you can reach out to us at any moment!</p>
<p><a href="https://bit.ly/3rIUO7z" target="_blank" title="EB70+SP200 Solar Generator Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer"><span style="color: #00aaff;"><strong> Explore Bluetti Solar Generator Kit Now! (EB70+SP200)</strong></span></a></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station</id>
    <published>2021-08-02T14:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:25:12+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station"/>
    <title>Why Should I Select BLUETTI Power Station?</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[The portable power station, likewise called the solar generator, battery generator, is a portable power gadget fitted with Lithium-ion battery cells and an A/C power inverter and supports several kinds of recharge approaches, including several kinds of solar power. A portable power station can power not simply your phones, laptop computers. Some high-power designs can also power a little a/c unit for hrs (Like the <a href="https://bit.ly/3k2bsdZ" target="_blank" title="bluetti-ac200p-power-station" rel="noopener noreferrer">BLUETTI AC200P</a>). Whether you take pleasure in roughing it on the weekends or reside in an area with constant blackouts, possessing a BLUETTI mobile power station is among the smartest investments you can make. Not only does it offer a reliable source of off-grid power, yet its capacity to be conveniently lugged allows it to go practically anywhere.
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/IG-0729-2-min.jpg?v=1628836169" alt="Bluetti AC200P On the car"></p>
<h1>What're its most significant advantages against gas-fired generators?</h1>
<p>Absolutely no exhausts. No co2, carbon monoxide, nitric oxide, etc. You can do not hesitate to utilize a mobile power station in a closed Motor Home carriage, yurt, camping tent, and your bedside. ( It is strictly prohibited to make use of a gas-fired generator in the shut room!).</p>
<p>Silent like a flooring fan, it get you with the summer evening power outages during heat waves, with no unbearable noise.</p>
<p>Free solar power input. Allow the sunlight fee all your fun!</p>
<h1>WHAT IS MPPT?</h1>
<p>MPPT( Max Power Point Monitoring) is an innovative solar charging controller that can considerably enhance solar charging performance. All of BLUETTI's mobile power stations are equipped with an MPPT controller.</p>
<h1>What is the open-circuit voltage of photovoltaic panels?</h1>
<p>Open-circuit voltage (abbreviated as OCV or VOC) is the distinction of the electrical possible in between 2 terminals of a photovoltaic panel when separated from any circuit. Greater OCV brings a quicker charging rate of the solar panel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/open_circuit_voltage_vs_closed_circuit_voltage-min.png?v=1628835928" alt="open circuit voltage vs closed circuit voltage-min"></p>
<h1>What is a pure sine wave inverter?</h1>
<p>An inverter is an electronic tool that transforms straight present (DC) to alternating current (A/C). A sine wave is a continuous wave that describes a smooth recurring oscillation. Conventional A/C power is created by turning makers and is mathematically referred to as a sine wave. It is the optimal waveform for the transfer of Air Conditioner power with really low harmonic distortion. Pure sine wave inverters produce power that amounts to or is better than the power in the house. All BLUETTI's mobile power stations have built-in pure sine wave inverters.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/waves-min.png?v=1628835988" alt="Waves"></p>
<h4><span style="color: #ffffff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/388Z7lZ" target="_blank" style="background-color: #00aaff; color: #ffffff;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Get Your Bluetti Power Station Now</strong>(AC200P)</a></span></h4>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021</id>
    <published>2021-08-01T10:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:26:49+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021"/>
    <title>Learn About the Background of Solar Power (1839 - 2021)</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>This post aims to discuss the history of solar energy, or instead of the photovoltaic result, and how it led to the mass production of photovoltaic panels.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The history of solar energy goes way back. Nevertheless, the Sun has to do with 4,603 billion years old!</p>
<p>Without the Sun, world earth would be a ball of ice with definitely no possibility of life.</p>
<p>Solar energy has been a feature of our Earth's background much before photovoltaic panels were invented.</p>
<p>Humanity has been harnessing it in different methods throughout the background, but so have pets and plants, for example, through photosynthesis.</p>
<p>This post aims to discuss the history of solar energy, or instead of the photovoltaic result, and how it led to the mass production of photovoltaic panels.</p>
<h1>WHAT IS THE SUNLIGHT?</h1>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/nasa-JHyiw_dpALk-unsplash-min_1.jpg?v=1628826468" alt=""></p>
<p>History of solar power.</p>
<p>The sunlight determines around 696,340 km in span and has a mass of <span>1.9891x10</span><sup>30</sup><span> kg = 4.384x10</span><sup>30</sup><span> lb = 2.192x10</span><sup>27</sup><span> tons</span>, or a mass 333,000 times that of the world Earth.</p>
<p>It is tremendous!</p>
<p>Its surface area temperature is 5,778 K. It can reach this temperature through nuclear combination reactions in its core.</p>
<p>These responses radiate power, which mainly takes visible light, ultraviolet light, and infrared radiation.</p>
<p>Regarding three-quarters of the sunlight's mass contains hydrogen (~ 73%). The remainder is comprised of primary helium (~ 25%), with much smaller quantities of more significant components, such as oxygen, carbon, neon, and iron.</p>
<p>The Sun's core fuses roughly 600 million lots of hydrogen right into helium every single second. This suggests that 4 million tons of issues are exchanged energy every second.</p>
<p>The energy released can take between 10,000 and 170,000 years to run away from the Sun's core. This is the resource of the sunlight's light and warmth that you and I feel today.</p>
<p>When the hydrogen combination in the sunlight's core has reduced to the factor at which it's no longer in a state hydrostatic balance, the core will enhance in thickness and temperature level. While this occurs, its external layers will expand, changing itself right into a red giant.</p>
<p>Scientists have computed that the sunlight will come to be large enough to engulf the current orbits of Mercury and Venus. Indeed, by the time this happens, Earth will no longer exist.</p>
<p>However, do not be distressed just yet, as this will only occur in the next 5 billion years.</p>
<p>After this has happened, it will undoubtedly lose its outer layers, becoming a thick air conditioning celebrity referred to as a white dwarf. It will no more generate energy via combination but will certainly still radiance and produce heat from its previous quantities of fusion.</p>
<h1>HISTORY OF SOLAR ENERGY.</h1>
<p>Now that we understand what the Sun is and how it develops its energy, we can much better recognize just how we could harness this power to begin with.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/History_of_solar_energy_2048x2048_e9a61842-f6c0-4e28-ae1d-e714c3098ab3.png?v=1628763490" alt="history of solar energy" style="float: none;"></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">History of solar energy.</p>
<h1>PHOTOVOLTAIC RESULT (1839 ).</h1>
<p>In 1893, the photovoltaic or PV result was discovered by a French physicist after 19 years of age, Alexandre-Edmond Becquerel.</p>
<p>He did so while trying out metal electrodes and electrolytes. During these experiments, Alexandre uncovered that conductance boosts with lighting.</p>
<p>He also understood practically no difference in the quantity of present under luminescent or dark problems.</p>
<p>It was at this moment he uncovered the absolute basics of the photovoltaic or PV impact. Nevertheless, it was not until much later that actual implementation would undoubtedly happen.</p>
<p>SOLAR-POWERED HEAVY STEAM ENGINES (1860'S).</p>
<p>Throughout the 1860s, French mathematician August Mouchet came up with the idea for vapor engines to be powered by solar power.</p>
<p>In complying with decades to come, he and his assistant Abel Pierre developed the very initial solar energy vapor engines. In fact, this type of invention ended up being the predecessors of contemporary allegorical dish enthusiasts.</p>
<h1>STRONG PRODUCT CONTAINERS CHANGE LIGHT INTO ELECTRICAL ENERGY (1876 ).</h1>
<p>In 1876, Richard Evans Day and William Grylls Adams initially discovered that selenium produces electrical energy when put in front of the light.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, selenium solar cells did not make the cut and also failed to transform enough sunlight into electricity; as a result, electric devices might not be powered with this technique.</p>
<p>With that being stated, both males undoubtedly determined that a strong product can transform light right into electrical power without warm or moving components.</p>
<h1>EINSTEIN RELEASES HIS PAPER ON THE PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT (1905 ).</h1>
<p>Professor Albert Einstein publishes his paper on the photoelectric effect, in addition to his concept of relativity.</p>
<p>It was this publication that sparked the drive-in of several researchers to come.</p>
<h1>PROOF OF THE PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT (1916 ).</h1>
<p>Robert Millikan gives actual speculative proof that the photoelectric result jobs.</p>
<h1>SINGLE CRYSTAL SILICON (1918 ).</h1>
<p>A Polish scientist named Jan Czochralski established a means to expand single-crystal silicon. There is even more information on Czochralski in this <a href="https://californiasolarcenter.org/history-solarthermal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">short article</a> called: Teacher Jan Czolchralski (1885-1953) as well as His Contribution to the Art and Science of Crystal Development.</p>
<h1>PASSIVE SOLAR STRUCTURES (1947 ).</h1>
<p>The prolonged W.W.II caused the demand for accessible solar structures in the USA to soar in appeal. This was as a result of the limited energy around (because of W.W.II).</p>
<p>Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Business chose to publish a publication named: Your Solar Home, which ultimately profiled forty-nine of the country's greatest solar designers.</p>
<h1>PHOTOVOLTAIC TECHNOLOGY IS BORN (1954 ).</h1>
<p>In 1954 Daryl Chapin, Calvin Richer, and Gerald Pearson lastly developed the silicon photovoltaic (PV) cell at Bell Labs.</p>
<p>This was the initial silicon solar battery efficient in transforming enough of the Sun's energy right into power to run daily electrical devices.</p>
<p>At first, the business silicon solar cells had an efficiency of 4%; however, later on, they could bump that efficiency as much as 11%.</p>
<h1>PROPOSAL FOR PLANET ORBITING SATELLITES (1956 ).</h1>
<p>In 1956, William Cherry, U.S. Signal Corps Laboratories, comes close to RCA Labs' Paul Rappaport and Joseph Loferski and asks them about the possibilities of creating solar batteries for orbiting Planet satellites.</p>
<h1>N ON P SILICON SOLAR CELLS (1958 ).</h1>
<p>T. Mandelkorn from the UNITED STATE Signal Corps Laboratories can produce n-on-p silicon solar batteries (this becomes vital for room cells; as they are more immune to radiation).</p>
<h1>LEAD 1 ROOM SATELLITE (1958 ).</h1>
<p>The Lead I area satellite used a really tiny (much less than one watt) solar variety to power its onboard radios.</p>
<p>Later that year, Traveler III, Lead II, and Sputnik-3 were introduced with PV-powered systems aboard.</p>
<p>In spite of lots of failed efforts to commercialize the silicon solar cell in the 1950s and 60s, it was made use of effectively in powering satellites. It came to be the accepted power source for room applications and stays so today.</p>
<h1>SOLAR CELL COST DECREASE (1970'S).</h1>
<p>Dr. Elliot Berman, with the aid of Exxon Company, creates a substantially much less pricey solar battery, bringing the rate down from $100 a watt to $20 a watt, a significant price reduction!</p>
<p>Solar cells begin to power navigating warning lights and also horns on numerous overseas gas and also oil rigs, lighthouses, railroad crossings, and also residential solar applications started to be viewed as sensible applications in remote locations where grid-connected energies can not exist economically.</p>
<h1>SOLAR ONE (1973 ).</h1>
<p>The University of Delaware constructs what's referred to as Solar One, among the world's very first PV-powered homes.</p>
<p>The system requires a PV/thermal crossbreed.</p>
<p>By having the roof-integrated solar varieties feed surplus power through a unique meter to the energy throughout the day and bought power from the energy during the night.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the actual ranges acted as flat-plate thermal enthusiasts, with fans blowing the warm air over the array to phase-change heat storage space containers.</p>
<h1>NREL IS BORN (1977 ).</h1>
<p>In 1977, the UNITED STATE Division of Power launched the Solar power Study Institute (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Renewable_Energy_Laboratory" target="_blank" title="National Renewable Energy Laboratory" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Renewable Resource Laboratory</a>).</p>
<h1>VOLKSWAGEN (1982 ).</h1>
<p>The German business Volkswagen begins examining photovoltaic panels on top of the Dasher terminal wagons' roofings. These systems might generate 160 watts for the ignition system.</p>
<p>GLOBE'S LARGEST SOLAR THERMAL FACILITY COMMISSIONED (1986 ).</p>
<p>In 1986, the world's biggest solar thermal center, which was located in Kramer Junction, The golden state, was commissioned.</p>
<p>The center consisted of areas that had rows of mirrors that focused the Sun's energy onto a system of pipes distributing a warmth transfer liquid.</p>
<p>This generated warm transfer liquid, which was then utilized to create vapor. This heavy steam-powered a conventional generator to generate electricity.</p>
<h1>NREL ESTABLISHES A BRAND-NEW SOLAR CELL (1994 ).</h1>
<p>The National Renewable Energy Lab develops a new solar battery made from the products gallium indium phosphide and gallium arsenide.</p>
<p>This solar battery becomes the initial one to surpass the 30% conversion performance.</p>
<h1>SOLAR II (1996 ).</h1>
<p>The US Division of Power starts taking control of Solar 2, which is an upgrade of its Solar One focusing solar energy tower task.</p>
<p>Solar II was run in 1999. This time, it demonstrated how solar power could be stored effectively as well as economically to ensure that power can also be generated when there was no energetic sun shining.</p>
<p>Solar II also produced a rate of interest in industrial power towers.</p>
<h1>A MORE EFFICIENT SOLAR CELL IS ESTABLISHED (1999 ).</h1>
<p>Spectrolab, in collaboration with the NREL, developed a photovoltaic solar battery that converts 32.3 percent of the sunshine that strikes it into electrical energy.</p>
<p>This high conversion rating was achieved by integrating three layers of photovoltaic materials right into a solitary solar battery.</p>
<p>In order to make use of these very effective solar batteries, one needs to have them placed in a device that makes use of lenses or mirrors to focus sunlight onto the cell.</p>
<p>These "concentrator" systems are placed on a track system that keeps them aimed toward the sunlight.</p>
<h1>SOLAR ELECTRIC CANOPIES ON GAS STATIONS (2002 ).</h1>
<p>British Oil (BP) and BP Solar introduced that they will be opening up a filling station in Indianapolis that features a solar-electric canopy.</p>
<p>The Indianapolis station is the first UNITED STATE "BP Connect" store, a model BP uses for all brand-new or substantially spruced-up BP filling stations.</p>
<p>The canopy includes translucent PV components made from thin-film silicon deposited onto glass.</p>
<h1>SOLAR TODAY (2021 ).</h1>
<p>China remains the world's largest PV market, with most photovoltaic panels being produced out of cities like Shenzhen and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Growth will certainly also proceed in the USA with recurring plan assistance at the government and also state level.</p>
<p>India's PV market experienced a substantial decline in brand-new solar PV capability additions in 2020 as an outcome of Covid-related delays. Nevertheless, the country is expected to recover rapidly in 2021.</p>
<p>Lastly, around the world, the solar PV electrical power generation is anticipated to increase by 145 TWh, virtually 18%, to come close to 1 000 TWh in 2021.</p>
<h1>FINAL THOUGHTS.</h1>
<p>Around the early 2000s, modern solar technology has actually removed to come to be a nationwide phenomenon.</p>
<p>Residential houses all over the globe are switching over to renewables by installing the most recent PV technology on the marketplace.</p>
<p>Not long ago, the US mounted its millionth solar setup.</p>
<p>It took the country 50 years to complete this task. However, it is anticipated that the number of solar setups mounted will certainly double in just two years.</p>
<p>Throughout the globe, new financing options appear for more extensive residential installations, solar panels themselves are ending up being more affordable, and also the top quality improving annually.</p>
<p>We hope you appreciated this short background of solar energy. If you would love to make the button yourself, get in touch with us.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #ffffff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3OttaoE" target="_blank" title="AC200MAX+3*SP200 Solar Generator Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #ffffff;"><strong><span style="background-color: #00aaff;">Get Your Bluetti Power Generator Now (AC200MAX+3SP200）</span></strong></a></span></h4>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
