<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/tagged/power-station.atom"/>
  <title>Bluettipower-EU - News</title>
  <updated>2022-10-24T17:30:00+08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bluettipower-EU</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station</id>
    <published>2021-08-02T14:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:25:12+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station"/>
    <title>Why Should I Select BLUETTI Power Station?</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[The portable power station, likewise called the solar generator, battery generator, is a portable power gadget fitted with Lithium-ion battery cells and an A/C power inverter and supports several kinds of recharge approaches, including several kinds of solar power. A portable power station can power not simply your phones, laptop computers. Some high-power designs can also power a little a/c unit for hrs (Like the <a href="https://bit.ly/3k2bsdZ" target="_blank" title="bluetti-ac200p-power-station" rel="noopener noreferrer">BLUETTI AC200P</a>). Whether you take pleasure in roughing it on the weekends or reside in an area with constant blackouts, possessing a BLUETTI mobile power station is among the smartest investments you can make. Not only does it offer a reliable source of off-grid power, yet its capacity to be conveniently lugged allows it to go practically anywhere.
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/IG-0729-2-min.jpg?v=1628836169" alt="Bluetti AC200P On the car"></p>
<h1>What're its most significant advantages against gas-fired generators?</h1>
<p>Absolutely no exhausts. No co2, carbon monoxide, nitric oxide, etc. You can do not hesitate to utilize a mobile power station in a closed Motor Home carriage, yurt, camping tent, and your bedside. ( It is strictly prohibited to make use of a gas-fired generator in the shut room!).</p>
<p>Silent like a flooring fan, it get you with the summer evening power outages during heat waves, with no unbearable noise.</p>
<p>Free solar power input. Allow the sunlight fee all your fun!</p>
<h1>WHAT IS MPPT?</h1>
<p>MPPT( Max Power Point Monitoring) is an innovative solar charging controller that can considerably enhance solar charging performance. All of BLUETTI's mobile power stations are equipped with an MPPT controller.</p>
<h1>What is the open-circuit voltage of photovoltaic panels?</h1>
<p>Open-circuit voltage (abbreviated as OCV or VOC) is the distinction of the electrical possible in between 2 terminals of a photovoltaic panel when separated from any circuit. Greater OCV brings a quicker charging rate of the solar panel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/open_circuit_voltage_vs_closed_circuit_voltage-min.png?v=1628835928" alt="open circuit voltage vs closed circuit voltage-min"></p>
<h1>What is a pure sine wave inverter?</h1>
<p>An inverter is an electronic tool that transforms straight present (DC) to alternating current (A/C). A sine wave is a continuous wave that describes a smooth recurring oscillation. Conventional A/C power is created by turning makers and is mathematically referred to as a sine wave. It is the optimal waveform for the transfer of Air Conditioner power with really low harmonic distortion. Pure sine wave inverters produce power that amounts to or is better than the power in the house. All BLUETTI's mobile power stations have built-in pure sine wave inverters.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/waves-min.png?v=1628835988" alt="Waves"></p>
<h4><span style="color: #ffffff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/388Z7lZ" target="_blank" style="background-color: #00aaff; color: #ffffff;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Get Your Bluetti Power Station Now</strong>(AC200P)</a></span></h4>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
