<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/tagged/solar-power.atom"/>
  <title>Bluettipower-EU - News</title>
  <updated>2022-10-24T17:30:00+08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Bluettipower-EU</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station</id>
    <published>2021-08-02T14:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:25:12+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/why-should-i-select-bluetti-power-station"/>
    <title>Why Should I Select BLUETTI Power Station?</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[The portable power station, likewise called the solar generator, battery generator, is a portable power gadget fitted with Lithium-ion battery cells and an A/C power inverter and supports several kinds of recharge approaches, including several kinds of solar power. A portable power station can power not simply your phones, laptop computers. Some high-power designs can also power a little a/c unit for hrs (Like the <a href="https://bit.ly/3k2bsdZ" target="_blank" title="bluetti-ac200p-power-station" rel="noopener noreferrer">BLUETTI AC200P</a>). Whether you take pleasure in roughing it on the weekends or reside in an area with constant blackouts, possessing a BLUETTI mobile power station is among the smartest investments you can make. Not only does it offer a reliable source of off-grid power, yet its capacity to be conveniently lugged allows it to go practically anywhere.
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/IG-0729-2-min.jpg?v=1628836169" alt="Bluetti AC200P On the car"></p>
<h1>What're its most significant advantages against gas-fired generators?</h1>
<p>Absolutely no exhausts. No co2, carbon monoxide, nitric oxide, etc. You can do not hesitate to utilize a mobile power station in a closed Motor Home carriage, yurt, camping tent, and your bedside. ( It is strictly prohibited to make use of a gas-fired generator in the shut room!).</p>
<p>Silent like a flooring fan, it get you with the summer evening power outages during heat waves, with no unbearable noise.</p>
<p>Free solar power input. Allow the sunlight fee all your fun!</p>
<h1>WHAT IS MPPT?</h1>
<p>MPPT( Max Power Point Monitoring) is an innovative solar charging controller that can considerably enhance solar charging performance. All of BLUETTI's mobile power stations are equipped with an MPPT controller.</p>
<h1>What is the open-circuit voltage of photovoltaic panels?</h1>
<p>Open-circuit voltage (abbreviated as OCV or VOC) is the distinction of the electrical possible in between 2 terminals of a photovoltaic panel when separated from any circuit. Greater OCV brings a quicker charging rate of the solar panel.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/open_circuit_voltage_vs_closed_circuit_voltage-min.png?v=1628835928" alt="open circuit voltage vs closed circuit voltage-min"></p>
<h1>What is a pure sine wave inverter?</h1>
<p>An inverter is an electronic tool that transforms straight present (DC) to alternating current (A/C). A sine wave is a continuous wave that describes a smooth recurring oscillation. Conventional A/C power is created by turning makers and is mathematically referred to as a sine wave. It is the optimal waveform for the transfer of Air Conditioner power with really low harmonic distortion. Pure sine wave inverters produce power that amounts to or is better than the power in the house. All BLUETTI's mobile power stations have built-in pure sine wave inverters.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/waves-min.png?v=1628835988" alt="Waves"></p>
<h4><span style="color: #ffffff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/388Z7lZ" target="_blank" style="background-color: #00aaff; color: #ffffff;" rel="noopener noreferrer"><strong>Get Your Bluetti Power Station Now</strong>(AC200P)</a></span></h4>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021</id>
    <published>2021-08-01T10:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-07-08T16:26:49+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021"/>
    <title>Learn About the Background of Solar Power (1839 - 2021)</title>
    <author>
      <name>steven sun</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>This post aims to discuss the history of solar energy, or instead of the photovoltaic result, and how it led to the mass production of photovoltaic panels.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.bluettipower.eu/blogs/news/learn-about-the-background-of-solar-power-1839-2021">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The history of solar energy goes way back. Nevertheless, the Sun has to do with 4,603 billion years old!</p>
<p>Without the Sun, world earth would be a ball of ice with definitely no possibility of life.</p>
<p>Solar energy has been a feature of our Earth's background much before photovoltaic panels were invented.</p>
<p>Humanity has been harnessing it in different methods throughout the background, but so have pets and plants, for example, through photosynthesis.</p>
<p>This post aims to discuss the history of solar energy, or instead of the photovoltaic result, and how it led to the mass production of photovoltaic panels.</p>
<h1>WHAT IS THE SUNLIGHT?</h1>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/nasa-JHyiw_dpALk-unsplash-min_1.jpg?v=1628826468" alt=""></p>
<p>History of solar power.</p>
<p>The sunlight determines around 696,340 km in span and has a mass of <span>1.9891x10</span><sup>30</sup><span> kg = 4.384x10</span><sup>30</sup><span> lb = 2.192x10</span><sup>27</sup><span> tons</span>, or a mass 333,000 times that of the world Earth.</p>
<p>It is tremendous!</p>
<p>Its surface area temperature is 5,778 K. It can reach this temperature through nuclear combination reactions in its core.</p>
<p>These responses radiate power, which mainly takes visible light, ultraviolet light, and infrared radiation.</p>
<p>Regarding three-quarters of the sunlight's mass contains hydrogen (~ 73%). The remainder is comprised of primary helium (~ 25%), with much smaller quantities of more significant components, such as oxygen, carbon, neon, and iron.</p>
<p>The Sun's core fuses roughly 600 million lots of hydrogen right into helium every single second. This suggests that 4 million tons of issues are exchanged energy every second.</p>
<p>The energy released can take between 10,000 and 170,000 years to run away from the Sun's core. This is the resource of the sunlight's light and warmth that you and I feel today.</p>
<p>When the hydrogen combination in the sunlight's core has reduced to the factor at which it's no longer in a state hydrostatic balance, the core will enhance in thickness and temperature level. While this occurs, its external layers will expand, changing itself right into a red giant.</p>
<p>Scientists have computed that the sunlight will come to be large enough to engulf the current orbits of Mercury and Venus. Indeed, by the time this happens, Earth will no longer exist.</p>
<p>However, do not be distressed just yet, as this will only occur in the next 5 billion years.</p>
<p>After this has happened, it will undoubtedly lose its outer layers, becoming a thick air conditioning celebrity referred to as a white dwarf. It will no more generate energy via combination but will certainly still radiance and produce heat from its previous quantities of fusion.</p>
<h1>HISTORY OF SOLAR ENERGY.</h1>
<p>Now that we understand what the Sun is and how it develops its energy, we can much better recognize just how we could harness this power to begin with.</p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0566/6396/5893/files/History_of_solar_energy_2048x2048_e9a61842-f6c0-4e28-ae1d-e714c3098ab3.png?v=1628763490" alt="history of solar energy" style="float: none;"></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">History of solar energy.</p>
<h1>PHOTOVOLTAIC RESULT (1839 ).</h1>
<p>In 1893, the photovoltaic or PV result was discovered by a French physicist after 19 years of age, Alexandre-Edmond Becquerel.</p>
<p>He did so while trying out metal electrodes and electrolytes. During these experiments, Alexandre uncovered that conductance boosts with lighting.</p>
<p>He also understood practically no difference in the quantity of present under luminescent or dark problems.</p>
<p>It was at this moment he uncovered the absolute basics of the photovoltaic or PV impact. Nevertheless, it was not until much later that actual implementation would undoubtedly happen.</p>
<p>SOLAR-POWERED HEAVY STEAM ENGINES (1860'S).</p>
<p>Throughout the 1860s, French mathematician August Mouchet came up with the idea for vapor engines to be powered by solar power.</p>
<p>In complying with decades to come, he and his assistant Abel Pierre developed the very initial solar energy vapor engines. In fact, this type of invention ended up being the predecessors of contemporary allegorical dish enthusiasts.</p>
<h1>STRONG PRODUCT CONTAINERS CHANGE LIGHT INTO ELECTRICAL ENERGY (1876 ).</h1>
<p>In 1876, Richard Evans Day and William Grylls Adams initially discovered that selenium produces electrical energy when put in front of the light.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, selenium solar cells did not make the cut and also failed to transform enough sunlight into electricity; as a result, electric devices might not be powered with this technique.</p>
<p>With that being stated, both males undoubtedly determined that a strong product can transform light right into electrical power without warm or moving components.</p>
<h1>EINSTEIN RELEASES HIS PAPER ON THE PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT (1905 ).</h1>
<p>Professor Albert Einstein publishes his paper on the photoelectric effect, in addition to his concept of relativity.</p>
<p>It was this publication that sparked the drive-in of several researchers to come.</p>
<h1>PROOF OF THE PHOTOELECTRIC EFFECT (1916 ).</h1>
<p>Robert Millikan gives actual speculative proof that the photoelectric result jobs.</p>
<h1>SINGLE CRYSTAL SILICON (1918 ).</h1>
<p>A Polish scientist named Jan Czochralski established a means to expand single-crystal silicon. There is even more information on Czochralski in this <a href="https://californiasolarcenter.org/history-solarthermal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">short article</a> called: Teacher Jan Czolchralski (1885-1953) as well as His Contribution to the Art and Science of Crystal Development.</p>
<h1>PASSIVE SOLAR STRUCTURES (1947 ).</h1>
<p>The prolonged W.W.II caused the demand for accessible solar structures in the USA to soar in appeal. This was as a result of the limited energy around (because of W.W.II).</p>
<p>Libbey-Owens-Ford Glass Business chose to publish a publication named: Your Solar Home, which ultimately profiled forty-nine of the country's greatest solar designers.</p>
<h1>PHOTOVOLTAIC TECHNOLOGY IS BORN (1954 ).</h1>
<p>In 1954 Daryl Chapin, Calvin Richer, and Gerald Pearson lastly developed the silicon photovoltaic (PV) cell at Bell Labs.</p>
<p>This was the initial silicon solar battery efficient in transforming enough of the Sun's energy right into power to run daily electrical devices.</p>
<p>At first, the business silicon solar cells had an efficiency of 4%; however, later on, they could bump that efficiency as much as 11%.</p>
<h1>PROPOSAL FOR PLANET ORBITING SATELLITES (1956 ).</h1>
<p>In 1956, William Cherry, U.S. Signal Corps Laboratories, comes close to RCA Labs' Paul Rappaport and Joseph Loferski and asks them about the possibilities of creating solar batteries for orbiting Planet satellites.</p>
<h1>N ON P SILICON SOLAR CELLS (1958 ).</h1>
<p>T. Mandelkorn from the UNITED STATE Signal Corps Laboratories can produce n-on-p silicon solar batteries (this becomes vital for room cells; as they are more immune to radiation).</p>
<h1>LEAD 1 ROOM SATELLITE (1958 ).</h1>
<p>The Lead I area satellite used a really tiny (much less than one watt) solar variety to power its onboard radios.</p>
<p>Later that year, Traveler III, Lead II, and Sputnik-3 were introduced with PV-powered systems aboard.</p>
<p>In spite of lots of failed efforts to commercialize the silicon solar cell in the 1950s and 60s, it was made use of effectively in powering satellites. It came to be the accepted power source for room applications and stays so today.</p>
<h1>SOLAR CELL COST DECREASE (1970'S).</h1>
<p>Dr. Elliot Berman, with the aid of Exxon Company, creates a substantially much less pricey solar battery, bringing the rate down from $100 a watt to $20 a watt, a significant price reduction!</p>
<p>Solar cells begin to power navigating warning lights and also horns on numerous overseas gas and also oil rigs, lighthouses, railroad crossings, and also residential solar applications started to be viewed as sensible applications in remote locations where grid-connected energies can not exist economically.</p>
<h1>SOLAR ONE (1973 ).</h1>
<p>The University of Delaware constructs what's referred to as Solar One, among the world's very first PV-powered homes.</p>
<p>The system requires a PV/thermal crossbreed.</p>
<p>By having the roof-integrated solar varieties feed surplus power through a unique meter to the energy throughout the day and bought power from the energy during the night.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the actual ranges acted as flat-plate thermal enthusiasts, with fans blowing the warm air over the array to phase-change heat storage space containers.</p>
<h1>NREL IS BORN (1977 ).</h1>
<p>In 1977, the UNITED STATE Division of Power launched the Solar power Study Institute (<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Renewable_Energy_Laboratory" target="_blank" title="National Renewable Energy Laboratory" rel="noopener noreferrer">National Renewable Resource Laboratory</a>).</p>
<h1>VOLKSWAGEN (1982 ).</h1>
<p>The German business Volkswagen begins examining photovoltaic panels on top of the Dasher terminal wagons' roofings. These systems might generate 160 watts for the ignition system.</p>
<p>GLOBE'S LARGEST SOLAR THERMAL FACILITY COMMISSIONED (1986 ).</p>
<p>In 1986, the world's biggest solar thermal center, which was located in Kramer Junction, The golden state, was commissioned.</p>
<p>The center consisted of areas that had rows of mirrors that focused the Sun's energy onto a system of pipes distributing a warmth transfer liquid.</p>
<p>This generated warm transfer liquid, which was then utilized to create vapor. This heavy steam-powered a conventional generator to generate electricity.</p>
<h1>NREL ESTABLISHES A BRAND-NEW SOLAR CELL (1994 ).</h1>
<p>The National Renewable Energy Lab develops a new solar battery made from the products gallium indium phosphide and gallium arsenide.</p>
<p>This solar battery becomes the initial one to surpass the 30% conversion performance.</p>
<h1>SOLAR II (1996 ).</h1>
<p>The US Division of Power starts taking control of Solar 2, which is an upgrade of its Solar One focusing solar energy tower task.</p>
<p>Solar II was run in 1999. This time, it demonstrated how solar power could be stored effectively as well as economically to ensure that power can also be generated when there was no energetic sun shining.</p>
<p>Solar II also produced a rate of interest in industrial power towers.</p>
<h1>A MORE EFFICIENT SOLAR CELL IS ESTABLISHED (1999 ).</h1>
<p>Spectrolab, in collaboration with the NREL, developed a photovoltaic solar battery that converts 32.3 percent of the sunshine that strikes it into electrical energy.</p>
<p>This high conversion rating was achieved by integrating three layers of photovoltaic materials right into a solitary solar battery.</p>
<p>In order to make use of these very effective solar batteries, one needs to have them placed in a device that makes use of lenses or mirrors to focus sunlight onto the cell.</p>
<p>These "concentrator" systems are placed on a track system that keeps them aimed toward the sunlight.</p>
<h1>SOLAR ELECTRIC CANOPIES ON GAS STATIONS (2002 ).</h1>
<p>British Oil (BP) and BP Solar introduced that they will be opening up a filling station in Indianapolis that features a solar-electric canopy.</p>
<p>The Indianapolis station is the first UNITED STATE "BP Connect" store, a model BP uses for all brand-new or substantially spruced-up BP filling stations.</p>
<p>The canopy includes translucent PV components made from thin-film silicon deposited onto glass.</p>
<h1>SOLAR TODAY (2021 ).</h1>
<p>China remains the world's largest PV market, with most photovoltaic panels being produced out of cities like Shenzhen and Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Growth will certainly also proceed in the USA with recurring plan assistance at the government and also state level.</p>
<p>India's PV market experienced a substantial decline in brand-new solar PV capability additions in 2020 as an outcome of Covid-related delays. Nevertheless, the country is expected to recover rapidly in 2021.</p>
<p>Lastly, around the world, the solar PV electrical power generation is anticipated to increase by 145 TWh, virtually 18%, to come close to 1 000 TWh in 2021.</p>
<h1>FINAL THOUGHTS.</h1>
<p>Around the early 2000s, modern solar technology has actually removed to come to be a nationwide phenomenon.</p>
<p>Residential houses all over the globe are switching over to renewables by installing the most recent PV technology on the marketplace.</p>
<p>Not long ago, the US mounted its millionth solar setup.</p>
<p>It took the country 50 years to complete this task. However, it is anticipated that the number of solar setups mounted will certainly double in just two years.</p>
<p>Throughout the globe, new financing options appear for more extensive residential installations, solar panels themselves are ending up being more affordable, and also the top quality improving annually.</p>
<p>We hope you appreciated this short background of solar energy. If you would love to make the button yourself, get in touch with us.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #ffffff;"><a href="https://bit.ly/3OttaoE" target="_blank" title="AC200MAX+3*SP200 Solar Generator Kit" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #ffffff;"><strong><span style="background-color: #00aaff;">Get Your Bluetti Power Generator Now (AC200MAX+3SP200）</span></strong></a></span></h4>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
